<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
 <ondexdata xmlns:ondex="http://ondex.sourceforge.net/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://ondex.sourceforge.net/ ondex.xsd">
  <version>1.3</version>
  <ondexmetadata>
    <cvs>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0903</id>
        <fullname>mpidb</fullname>
        <description>"The microbial protein-protein interactions database (MPDIB) aims to collect and provide all known physical prokaryotic interactions." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0805</id>
        <fullname>wwpdb</fullname>
        <description>"The Worldwide Protein Data Bank (wwPDB) consists of organizations that act as deposition, data processing and distribution centers for PDB data. The founding members are RCSB PDB (USA), MSD-EBI (Europe) and PDBj (Japan). The BMRB (USA) group joined the wwPDB in 2006. The mission of the wwPDB is to maintain a single Protein Data Bank Archive of macromolecular structural data that is freely and publicly available to the global community.\nhttp://www.wwpdb.org/" [PMID:14634627]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0702</id>
        <fullname>panther</fullname>
        <description>"The PANTHER (Protein ANalysis THrough Evolutionary Relationships) Classification System is a unique resource that classifies genes by their functions using published scientific experimental evidence and evolutionary relationships to predict function even in the absence of direct experimental evidence.\nwww.pantherdb.org/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0742</id>
        <fullname>gpm</fullname>
        <description>"Global Proteome Machine aim to improve the quality of analysis, make the results portable and to provide a common platform for testing and validating proteomics results.\nhttp://www.thegpm.org" [PMID:15595733]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0741</id>
        <fullname>peptide atlas</fullname>
        <description>"PeptideAtlas addresses these needs by identifying peptides by tandem mass spectrometry (MS/MS), statistically validating those identifications and then mapping identified sequences to the genomes of eukaryotic organisms.\nhttp://www.peptideatlas.org/" [PMID:15642101, PMID:16381952]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0703</id>
        <fullname>gene3d</fullname>
        <description>"The Gene3D database provides a combined structural, functional and evolutionary view of the protein world. It is focused on providing structural annotation for protein sequences without structural representatives--including the complete proteome sets of over 240 different species.\nhttp://cathwww.biochem.ucl.ac.uk:8080/Gene3D/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0450</id>
        <fullname>cdd</fullname>
        <description>"The Conserved Domain Database may be used to identify the conserved domains present in a protein sequence.\nhttp://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Structure/cdd/cdd.shtml" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0849</id>
        <fullname>ncbi taxonomy</fullname>
        <description>"The NCBI taxonomy database indexes over 55 000 organisms that are represented in the sequence databases with at least one nucleotide or protein sequence. The Taxonomy Browser can be used to view the taxonomic position or retrieve sequence and structural data for a particular organism or group of organisms. Searches of the NCBI taxonomy may be made on the basis of whole or partial organism names, and direct links to organisms commonly used in biological research are also provided. The Taxonomy Browser can also be used to display the number of nucleic acid sequences, protein sequences, and protein structures available for organisms included in the branch. From the data display for a particular organism, one can retrieve and download the sequence data for that organism, or protein 3D structure data if available.\nhttp://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Taxonomy/" [PMID:10592169]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0585</id>
        <fullname>intenz</fullname>
        <description>"IntEnz is the name for the Integrated relational Enzyme database and is the official version of the Enzyme Nomenclature. The Enzyme Nomenclature comprises recommendations of the Nomenclature Committee of the International Union of Bio chemistry and Molecular Biology (NC-IUBMB) on the nomenclature and classification of enzyme-catalysed reactions. IntEnz is supported by NC-IUBMB and contains enzyme data curated and approved by this committee. The database IntEnz is available at.\nhttp://www.ebi.ac.uk/intenz" [PMID:14681451]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0452</id>
        <fullname>pirsf</fullname>
        <description>"PIRSF is a classification system based on evolutionary relationship of whole proteins.\nhttp://pir.georgetown.edu/pirwww/dbinfo/pirsf.shtml" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0304</id>
        <fullname>isoform synonym</fullname>
        <description>"Isoform synonym." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0592</id>
        <fullname>ipfam</fullname>
        <description>"Web resource that allows the investigation of protein interactions in the Protein Data Bank structures at the level of Pfam domains and amino acid residues. iPfam is available on the Web for browsing at.\nhttp://www.sanger.ac.uk/Software/Pfam/iPfam/" [PMID:15353450]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0303</id>
        <fullname>gene ontology synonym</fullname>
        <description>"Synonym as used in Gene Ontology." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0306</id>
        <fullname>open reading frame name</fullname>
        <description>"A name temporarily attributed by a sequencing project to an open reading frame. This name is generally based on a cosmid numbering system." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0305</id>
        <fullname>ordered locus name</fullname>
        <description>"A name used to represent an ORF in a completely sequenced genome or chromosome. It is generally based on a prefix representing the organism and a number which usually represents the sequential ordering of genes on the chromosome. Depending on the genome sequencing center, numbers are attributed only to protein-coding genes, or also to pseudogenes, or also to tRNAs and other features." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0447</id>
        <fullname>feature database</fullname>
        <description>"A database describing a feature on a molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0302</id>
        <fullname>gene name synonym</fullname>
        <description>"Gene name synonym." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0301</id>
        <fullname>gene name</fullname>
        <description>"Gene name." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0942</id>
        <fullname>uniprot taxonomy</fullname>
        <description>"Based on NCBO Taxonomy but adapted for UniProt\nhttp://www.uniprot.org/taxonomy/" [PMID:18836194]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0345</id>
        <fullname>author assigned name</fullname>
        <description>"Name assigned to a molecule by the authors within a paper that may differ from the reference database." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0737</id>
        <fullname>peptide sequence database</fullname>
        <description>"database storing sequences detected by peptide identification methods." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0673</id>
        <fullname>complex-synonym</fullname>
        <description>"Alternative names to describe a complex." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0738</id>
        <fullname>pride</fullname>
        <description>"PRIDE is a public repository of protein and peptide identifications for the proteomics community.\nhttp://www.ebi.ac.uk/pride/" [PMID:16381953]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0830</id>
        <fullname>tissue list</fullname>
        <description>"List of tissue used as  topic in UniProt RC line.\nhttp://www.expasy.org/cgi-bin/lists?tisslist.txt" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2017</id>
        <fullname>heterogen</fullname>
        <description>"The HET records are used to describe non-standard residues, such as prosthetic groups, inhibitors, solvent molecules, and ions for\nwhich coordinates are supplied. Groups are considered HET if they are: \n- not one of the standard amino acids, and \n- not one of the nucleic acids (C, G, A, T, U, and I), and \n- not one of the modified versions of nucleic acids (+C, +G, +A,\n+T, +U, and +I), and \n- not an unknown amino acid or nucleic acid where UNK is used to\nindicate the unknown residue name. \nHet records also describe heterogens for which the chemical identity is unknown, in which case the group is assigned the hetID UNK." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0475</id>
        <fullname>ddbj/embl/genbank</fullname>
        <description>"DDBJ EMBL GenBank Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration exchange new and updated data on a daily basis to achieve optimal synchronisation.\nhttp://www.ebi.ac.uk/embl/Contact/collaboration" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2015</id>
        <fullname>pharmgkb</fullname>
        <description>"Pharmacogenomics Knowledge Base identification number (if molecule is in PharmGKB)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0731</id>
        <fullname>3d repertoire</fullname>
        <description>"The aim of 3D Repertoire is to determine the structures of all amenable complexes in a cell at medium or high resolution, which will later serve to integrate in toponomic and dynamic analyses of protein complexes in a cell. Complex models, EM pictures, expression and purification protocols obtained in the project will be collected in a database connected to the PDB repository." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0477</id>
        <fullname>entrez gene/locuslink</fullname>
        <description>"LocusLink provides a single query interface to curated sequence and descriptive information about genetic loci.\nhttp://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/LocusLink/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2016</id>
        <fullname>bind smid</fullname>
        <description>"BIND database Small Molecule Identification number (if molecule is in BIND)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2021</id>
        <fullname>rxlist link</fullname>
        <description>"Hyperlink to RxList entry for the given drug (if it exists)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2020</id>
        <fullname>canadian drug identification number</fullname>
        <description>"Drug Identification Number (Canadian Drug ID system)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0481</id>
        <fullname>refseq</fullname>
        <description>"The Reference Sequence (RefSeq) collection aims to provide a comprehensive, integrated, non-redundant set of sequences, including genomic DNA, transcript (RNA), and protein products, for a number of organisms.\nhttp://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/RefSeq/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0482</id>
        <fullname>rfam</fullname>
        <description>"Rfam is a large collection of multiple sequence alignments and covariance models covering many common non-coding RNA families.\nhttp://www.sanger.ac.uk/Software/Rfam/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0936</id>
        <fullname>emdb</fullname>
        <description>"The Electron Microscopy Data Bank (EMDB) contains experimentally determined three-dimensional maps and associated experimental data and files." [PMID:14643225]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0973</id>
        <fullname>imex source</fullname>
        <description>"Databases that contain curated experimental interaction data and exchanging it with other IMEx databases." [PMID:17893861]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0683</id>
        <fullname>sequence database</fullname>
        <description>"Database collecting nucleic or amino acid sequences mainly derived from genomic or mRNA sequencing." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0974</id>
        <fullname>innatedb</fullname>
        <description>"Human and mouse experimentally verified interactions and pathways involved in innate immunity." [PMID:18766178]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0864</id>
        <fullname>brenda</fullname>
        <description>"A structured controlled vocabulary for the source of an enzyme. It comprises terms for tissues, cell lines, cell types and cell cultures from uni- and multicellular organisms.\nhttp://www.brenda-enzymes.info" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2004</id>
        <fullname>drug brand name</fullname>
        <description>"Alternate names of the drug, brand names from different manufacturers." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2005</id>
        <fullname>drug mixture brand name</fullname>
        <description>"Brand names and composition of mixtures that include the drug described in this DrugCard file." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2007</id>
        <fullname>iupac name</fullname>
        <description>"IUPAC or standard chemical name for a drug, or a chemical." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0468</id>
        <fullname>hprd</fullname>
        <description>"The Human Protein Reference Database represents a centralized platform to visually depict and integrate information pertaining to domain architecture, post-translational modifications, interaction networks and disease association for each protein in the human proteome.\nhttp://www.hprd.org/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0670</id>
        <fullname>imex</fullname>
        <description>"International Molecular Interaction Exchange." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2012</id>
        <fullname>kegg compound</fullname>
        <description>"Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes compound identification number (if molecule is in KEGG)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0465</id>
        <fullname>dip</fullname>
        <description>"The database of interacting protein (DIP) database stores experimentally determined interactions between proteins. It combines information from a variety of sources to create a single, consistent set of protein-protein interactions.\nhttp://dip.doe-mbi.ucla.edu/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2011</id>
        <fullname>cas registry number</fullname>
        <description>"Chemical Abstract Service identification number" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2054</id>
        <fullname>bioactive entity reference</fullname>
        <description>"General on-line reference to other details about a drug or other bioactive entity." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0967</id>
        <fullname>chembl</fullname>
        <description>"ChEMBL focuses on mapping the interactions of small molecules binding to their macromolecular targets." [PMID:19194660]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0897</id>
        <fullname>protein modification ontology</fullname>
        <description>"Catalogue of covalent modification of, or a change resulting in an alteration of the measured molecular mass of, a peptide or protein amino acid residue." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2153</id>
        <fullname>pdr health</fullname>
        <description>"Hyperlink to PDRhealth entry for the given drug (if it exists)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0923</id>
        <fullname>irefindex</fullname>
        <description>"iRefIndex provides an index of protein interactions available in a number of primary interaction databases including BIND, BioGRID, DIP, HPRD, IntAct, MINT, MPact, MPPI and OPHID.  This index allows the user to search for a protein and retrieve a non-redundant list of interactors for that protein. iRefIndex uses the Sequence Global Unique Identifier (SEGUID) to group proteins and interactions into redundant groups.  This method allows users to integrate their own data with the iRefIndex in a way that ensures proteins with the exact same sequence will be represented only once.\nhttp://irefindex.uio.no/" [PMID:18823568]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0924</id>
        <fullname>camjedb</fullname>
        <description>"Camjedb is a comprehensive database for information on the genome of Campylobacter jejuni.\nhttp://www.sanger.ac.uk/Projects/C_jejuni/" [PMID:106882042]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0850</id>
        <fullname>encode</fullname>
        <description>"ENCODE (the Encyclopedia Of DNA Elements) seeks to identify all protein-coding genes. The current ENCODE data set is derived from 1% of the human genome and has been selected for analysis in the pilot phase of the project.\nhttp://www.genome.gov/10005107" [PMID:17372197]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0463</id>
        <fullname>grid</fullname>
        <description>"The General Repository for Interaction Datasets (GRID) is a database of genetic and physical interactions.\nhttp://biodata.mshri.on.ca/grid" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0462</id>
        <fullname>bind</fullname>
        <description>"The Biomolecular Interaction Network Database (BIND) is a collection of records documenting molecular interactions.\nhttp://www.blueprint.org/bind" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0460</id>
        <fullname>rcsb pdb</fullname>
        <description>"The RCSB PDB provides a variety of tools and resources for studying the structures of biological macromolecules and their relationships to sequence, function, and disease. \nhttp://www.pdb.org/" [PMID:14634627]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>unknown</id>
        <fullname>unknown</fullname>
        <description>unknown data source</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0459</id>
        <fullname>mmdb</fullname>
        <description>"MMDB (Molecular Modeling DataBase), is a subset of three-dimensional structures obtained from the Protein Data Bank.\nhttp://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Structure" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0458</id>
        <fullname>tigrfams</fullname>
        <description>"TIGRFAMs is a collection of protein families, featuring curated multiple sequence alignments, Hidden Markov Models (HMMs) and annotation.\nhttp://www.tigr.org/TIGRFAMs" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0455</id>
        <fullname>prosite</fullname>
        <description>"PROSITE is a database of protein families and domains. It consists of biologically significant sites, patterns and profiles.\nhttp://us.expasy.org/prosite/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2003</id>
        <fullname>commercial name</fullname>
        <description>"Standard name of drug or any reagent as provided by its manufacturer." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0244</id>
        <fullname>reactome complex</fullname>
        <description>"Collection of functional complexes within Reactome - a knowledgebase of biological processes.\nhttp://www.reactome.org/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:2002</id>
        <fullname>drugbank</fullname>
        <description>"DrugBank Accession number consisting of the 4 letter prefix and a 5 number suffix. Each Accession number is unique to the drug's generic name. The 4 letter suffix (APRD, EXPT, BIOD, NUTR) indicates the type of drug (APRD=approved small molecule drug, EXPT=experimental drug, BIOD=biotech drug, NUTR=nutraceutical or natural product). Biotech drugs consist of FDA approved peptide, protein or nucleic acid drugs, approved small molecule drugs are FDA approved non-biotech drugs, nutraceuticals are natural products (amino acids, vitamins, other metabolites) and experimental drugs include drugs under trial, pre-clinical drugs, unapproved drugs, well known inhibitors and possible toxins." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0245</id>
        <fullname>reactome protein</fullname>
        <description>"Collection of protein within the Reactome database - a knowledgebase of biological processes.\nhttp://www.reactome.org/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0246</id>
        <fullname>cabri</fullname>
        <description>"CABRI cell lines catalogue available at.\nhttp://www.cabri.org/" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0247</id>
        <fullname>newt</fullname>
        <description>!Obsolete! New EBI Web Taxonomy</description>
      </cv>
      <cv>
        <id>MI:0917</id>
        <fullname>matrixdb</fullname>
        <description>"Knowledgebase of the extracellular matrix storing experimentally determined interactions involving extracellular biomolecules. It includes protein-protein, protein-polysaccharide, and protein-lipid interactions." [PMID:19147664]</description>
      </cv>
    </cvs>
    <units>
      <unit>
        <id>second</id>
        <fullname>second</fullname>
        <description>SI BASE Unit of time</description>
      </unit>
    </units>
    <attrnames>
      <attrname>
        <id>GDS</id>
        <fullname>GDS</fullname>
        <description>General data store</description>
        <datatype>java.lang.Object</datatype>
        <datatype>java.lang.Object</datatype>
      </attrname>
      <attrname>
        <id>confidences</id>
        <fullname>confidences</fullname>
        <description>A map containing several confidence statements, linking a unit to its value.</description>
        <datatype>java.util.Map</datatype>
        <datatype>java.util.Map</datatype>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>GDS</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </attrname>
      <attrname>
        <id>negative</id>
        <fullname>negative</fullname>
        <description>If true, this interaction has been shown not to occur under the described experimental conditions. If missing this element is assumed to be false.</description>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>GDS</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </attrname>
      <attrname>
        <id>modelled</id>
        <fullname>modelled</fullname>
        <description>If true, this element describes an interaction in a species of interest, but has actually been investigated in another organism. If this optional element is missing it is assumed to be set to false</description>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>GDS</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </attrname>
      <attrname>
        <id>intraMolecular</id>
        <fullname>intraMolecular</fullname>
        <description>If true, this interaction is a intramolecular interaction, e.g. an autophosphorylation. If missing this element is assumed to be false</description>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>GDS</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </attrname>
      <attrname>
        <id>inferred</id>
        <fullname>inferred</fullname>
        <description>Tags an inferred Interaction</description>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <datatype>java.lang.Boolean</datatype>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>GDS</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </attrname>
      <attrname>
        <id>existenceProbability</id>
        <fullname>existence probability</fullname>
        <description>Describes the probability of an element to really exist</description>
        <datatype>java.lang.Double</datatype>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>GDS</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </attrname>
    </attrnames>
    <evidences>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0808</id>
        <fullname>comigration in sds page</fullname>
        <description>"Method allowing the detection of strong interactions between two molecules by their very close proximity or the overlap of their relative bands in a denaturing SDS gel." [PMID:14755292, PMID:16732283]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0809</id>
        <fullname>bimolecular fluorescence complementation</fullname>
        <description>"The bimolecular fluorescence complementation (BiFC) is an assay for determination of the locations of protein interactions in living cells. This approach is based on complementation between two non fluorescent fragments of the yellow fluorescent protein (YFP) when they are brought together by interactions between proteins fused to each fragment." [PMID:11983170]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0686</id>
        <fullname>unspecified method</fullname>
        <description>"Yet to be identified interaction detection method associated with interaction data imported from a third party database. This database may have potentially different standards of curation." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0807</id>
        <fullname>comigration in gel electrophoresis</fullname>
        <description>"The interaction of two molecules is determine by their very close proximity or the overlap of their relative bands in a gel." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0990</id>
        <fullname>cleavage assay</fullname>
        <description>"The cleavage of a biomolecule either into its component parts or sub-parts." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0991</id>
        <fullname>lipid cleavage assay</fullname>
        <description>"The cleavage of a lipid molecule from a larger biomolecule." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0700</id>
        <fullname>rna directed rna polymerase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA (n) = diphosphate + RNA (n+1); uses an RNA template." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0588</id>
        <fullname>3 hybrid method</fullname>
        <description>"Group of method based on complementation assay where a third participant is shown to be necessary for the binding of a given bait prey pair." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0096</id>
        <fullname>pull down</fullname>
        <description>"A specific affinity chromatography method where a molecule of interest (bait) is expressed as a fusion to an affinity tag (GST, HIS tag and others) and binds to a support that has affinity for the tag. The protein may be expressed and purified first, often in an heterologous system, bound to the matrix at high concentration and then challenged with a solution or cellular extract containing the candidate partner molecules. Alternatively, a protein complex may be adsorbed to the resin and the retained binding proteins subsequently identified." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0406</id>
        <fullname>deacetylase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the hydrolysis of an acetyl group or groups from a substrate molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0095</id>
        <fullname>proteinchip(r) on a surface-enhanced laser desorption/ionization</fullname>
        <description>"ProteinChip(r) Array technology is a surface-enhanced laser desorption/ionization (SELDI) approach (Ciphergen Biosystems Inc. Fremont, CA, USA) for sample fractionation accomplished by retentate chromatography. Retentate chromatography is performed on ProteinChip Arrays with varying chromatographic properties (e.g. anion exchange, cation exchange, metal affinity and reverse phase). By utilising arrays with differing surface chemistries in parallel and in series, a complex mixture of proteins, as from cells or body fluids, can be resolved into subsets of proteins with common properties. Specific analytes can also be examined by using preactivated arrays to which a bait molecule (such as an antibody or biotinylated DNA) is immobilized and a solution containing the binding partner(s) is presented to the array. This array-based immunoprecipitation or protein-binding experiment has been used with good success to study DNA-binding proteins, receptor-ligand interactions, and protein complexes. Any ligand retained on a SELDI chip can directly be identified by mass spectrometry." [PMID:11827829]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0989</id>
        <fullname>amidation assay</fullname>
        <description>"The measurement of the addition of an amine group to a molecule." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0099</id>
        <fullname>scintillation proximity assay</fullname>
        <description>"SPA relies upon the fact that a beta particle emitted from a radioisotope decay can excite a fluorophore only when it is at a very short distance in water solution (few micrometers). The ligand is labelled with a radioactive atom and its potential partner is fixed to fluorophore containing beads, the emitted fluorescence proving their interaction can be measured in a scintillation counter. The scintillator measures only the amount of bound radiolabelled ligand. Competition experiment with cold competitor can be done to estimate the binding affinities (50% inhibitory concentration [IC50], cold ligand versus labelled ligand). Loss of signal can also be used to measure substrate cleavage by an enzyme, and labelled antibodies used to titrate the degree of modified residue present." [PMID:3866247]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0098</id>
        <fullname>ribosome display</fullname>
        <description>"This method permits the coupling of phenotype to genotype via the formation of a non-covalent ternary complex between mRNAs and their encoded polypeptides while they are translated in an in vitro system. As a first step a cDNA library is constructed that encodes chimeric proteins in which the natural proteins or protein domains are fused to a C-terminal tether. As a consequence when the mRNA is translated in vitro the domain can fold while the tether is still in the ribosomal tunnel. Furthermore this chimeric mRNAs lack a stop codon, thus preventing release of the mRNA and the polypeptide from the ribosome. High concentrations of magnesium and low temperature further stabilise the ternary complex. Similarly to phage display, these complexes can be used directly to select for nucleic acids encoding proteins with desired properties." [PMID:11551470, PMID for application instance:12167034]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0097</id>
        <fullname>reverse ras recruitment system</fullname>
        <description>"In this complementation approach the bait can be any membrane protein (for example a receptor or a channel protein), the prey is cloned as a fusion protein of any cDNA from a library and the coding sequence of cytoplasmic RAS (cdc25 in yeast). If the bait and the prey interact, RAS is recruited close to the membrane and can activate cell growth. This procedure must take place in cells having a mutated RAS (Cdc25-2 yeast strain having a temperature sensitive mutation of RAS) to avoid constitutive growth activation." [PMID:11160938]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0984</id>
        <fullname>deamination assay</fullname>
        <description>"The measurement of the removal of an amine group from a molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0983</id>
        <fullname>gemma</fullname>
        <description>"GEMMA is a method to study protein complexes in solution: a diluted protein sample is transmitted\ninto the gas phase by a charged reduced electrospray process. The generated particles, each\ncontaining one protein molecule with a +1 charge, are separated according to size in a differential\nmobility analyzer and subsequently quantified by a particle counter. In contrast to mass spectrometry,\nthis method is run at atmospheric pressure and measures the diameter of the particle rather than the mass." [PMID:16861739]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0401</id>
        <fullname>biochemical</fullname>
        <description>"The application of chemical principles and methods to biological experiments to demonstrate an interaction." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0982</id>
        <fullname>electrophoretic mobility-based method</fullname>
        <description>"Any method which relies on the motion of particles relative to a matrix under the influence of an electrical field." [PMID:19517512]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0400</id>
        <fullname>affinity technology</fullname>
        <description>"Techniques which depend upon the strength of the interaction between two entities." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0092</id>
        <fullname>protein in situ array</fullname>
        <description>"Protein In Situ Array is a method by which protein arrays are rapidly generated in one step directly from DNA, by cell-free protein expression and simultaneous in situ immobilisation at a surface. Individual genes or fragments are produce by PCR or RT-PCR depending on the source of genetic material using properly designed primers. The PISA is generated by cell-free protein synthesis using coupled transcription and translation to produce a double HexaHis-tagged protein, the reaction being carried out on a surface to which the protein adheres as soon as it is synthesised." [PMID:11470888]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0402</id>
        <fullname>chromatin immunoprecipitation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) is a powerful approach that allows one to define the interaction of factors with specific chromosomal sites in living cells. ChIP involves treating cells or tissue briefly with formaldehyde to crosslink proteins to DNA. An antibody against a protein suspected of binding a given cis-element is then used to immunoprecipitate chromatin fragments. Polymerase chain reaction analysis of the immunoprecipitate with primers flanking the cis-element reveals whether a specific DNA sequence is recovered in an immune-specific manner and therefore whether the protein contacted the site in living cells." [PMID:12054902]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0091</id>
        <fullname>chromatography technology</fullname>
        <description>"Used to separate and/or analyse complex mixtures. The components to be separated are distributed between two phases: a stationary phase (bed) and a mobile phase which percolates through the stationary bed. The nature of the two phases determines the separation criteria exploited by the column such as affinity, ionic charges, size or hydrophobicity of the molecules under analysis. Each type of column can be implemented with the mobile phase under atmospheric or high pressure condition. In this later case columns are designated as High Pressure Liquid Chromatography (HPLC)." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0405</id>
        <fullname>competition binding</fullname>
        <description>"Competitive binding experiments measure equilibrium binding of a single concentration of ligand at various concentrations of an unlabeled competitor. Analysis of these data gives the affinity of the receptor for the competitor." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0090</id>
        <fullname>protein complementation assay</fullname>
        <description>"The function of numerous proteins or ribonucleic particles (enzymes, transcription factors, and others) can be rationally dissected into two fragments that fold autonomously but cannot complement to reconstitute the complex function, unless they are located in close proximity. In a two hybrid experiment, restoration of the activity by complementation of the two fragments when expressed as fusion with two polypeptides is taken as an evidence that the two polypeptides interact together." [PMID:11495741]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0404</id>
        <fullname>comigration in non denaturing gel electrophoresis</fullname>
        <description>"comigration by non denaturing gel electrophoresis." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0676</id>
        <fullname>tandem affinity purification</fullname>
        <description>"Tandem affinity purification allows rapid purification under native conditions of complexes, even when expressed at their natural level. Prior knowledge of complex composition or function is not required. The TAP method requires fusion of the a multiple tag, either N- or C-terminally, to the target (or bait) protein of interest. The multiple tag allows two steps purification steps ensuring a highly selective complex purification." [PMID:11403571]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0678</id>
        <fullname>antibody array</fullname>
        <description>"A microarray consisting of antibodies spotted on a solid support in appropriate orientation is incubated with a biological sample (or antigen). Some proteins are captured by the antibodies in the array. Protein of  forming complexes on the array are identified according to their prior labelling (tag, ELISA, biotin and others)." [PMID:12454649]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0979</id>
        <fullname>oxidoreductase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Catalysis of oxido-reductions. The substrate oxidized is regarded as the hydrogen or electron donor. The classification is based on 'donor:acceptor oxidoreductase'. The common name is 'dehydrogenase', wherever this is possible; as an alternative, 'acceptor reductase' can be used. 'Oxidase' is used only where O2 is an acceptor." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0085</id>
        <fullname>phylogenetic profile</fullname>
        <description>"The phylogenetic profile of a protein stores information about the presence and the absence of that protein in a set of genomes. By clustering identical or similar profiles, proteins with similar functions and potentially interacting are identified." [PMID:10200254]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0084</id>
        <fullname>phage display</fullname>
        <description>"Peptide sequences or entire proteins can be displayed on phage capsids by fusion to coat proteins to generate a library of fusion phages each displaying a different peptide. Such a library can then be exploited to identify specific phages that display peptides that bind to any given bait molecule for instance an antibody. The selection is performed by a series of cycles of affinity purification known as panning. The bait protein, immobilized on a solid support (plastic, agarose, sepharose, magnetic beads and others) is soaked in the phage mixture and that phage that remains attached to the bait is amplified and carried through a further affinity purification step. Each cycle results in an approximately 1,000-fold enrichment of specific phage and after a few selection rounds (2-4), DNA sequencing of the tight-binding phage reveals only a small number of sequences. Phage display panning experiments can be carried out either on libraries of peptides of random amino acid sequence or on libraries of displaying natural peptides obtained by inserting cDNA fragments into the phage vector (cDNA libraries). Libraries have been assembled on several different phages (Fd, Lambda or T7)." [PMID:10975452, PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0087</id>
        <fullname>predictive text mining</fullname>
        <description>"Methods based on natural language processing to detect possible interactions between proteins (direct physical interactions or indirect genetic interactions). This includes the detection of non ambiguous protein or gene names and analysis of the relation expressed in a sentence among them." [PMID:11791231]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0089</id>
        <fullname>protein array</fullname>
        <description>"The protein array technology allows the screening of biochemical activities or binding abilities of hundreds or thousands of protein samples in parallel. After synthesis and purification by high-throughput methodologies, the proteins are printed onto the chip by using an instrument (micro-arrayer) that is capable of spotting liquid samples in a reproducible manner onto a planar support. The ordered protein array can then be probed with labelled molecules to identify proteins that bind to the bait." [PMID:10976071, PMID:12067604]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0972</id>
        <fullname>phosphopantetheinylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Assay of the posttranslational phosphopantetheinylation of peptidyl-serine to form peptidyl-O-phosphopantetheine-L-serine." [PMID:19346479]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0081</id>
        <fullname>peptide array</fullname>
        <description>"The peptide synthesis methods offer numerous opportunities to synthesise and subsequently screen large arrays of synthetic peptides on planar cellulose supports. Discrete spots are arranged as arrays on membrane sheets where each spot is individually accessed by manual or automated delivery of the appropriate reagent solutions. Over the past few years protein-protein recognition, peptide-metal ion interactions, peptide-nucleic acid binding, enzymatic modification of peptides experiments, have been explored using synthetic peptide arrays on planar support." [PMID:11167074]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0976</id>
        <fullname>total internal reflection fluorescence spectroscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Used to study surface-associated interactions at the molecular level. In this method, the evanescent field from an internally reflected excitation source selectively excites fluorescent molecules on or near a surface." [PMID:9013655]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0826</id>
        <fullname>x ray scattering</fullname>
        <description>"Method where the internal structure of a sample is derived from the intensity distribution of the scattered monochromatic X-ray beam at very low scattering angles." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0827</id>
        <fullname>x-ray tomography</fullname>
        <description>"X-ray Tomography is a branch of X-ray microscopy. A series of projection images are used to calculate a three dimensional reconstruction of an object. The technique has found many applications in materials science and later in biology and biomedical research. In terms of the latter, the National Center for X-ray Tomography (NCXT) is one of the principle developers of this technology, in particular for imaging whole, hydrated cells." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0824</id>
        <fullname>x-ray powder diffraction</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of a diffraction pattern generated by an isotropic sample composed of many randomly oriented crystals." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0430</id>
        <fullname>nucleic acid uv cross-linking assay</fullname>
        <description>"Radiolabelled nucleic acids with a known sequence are incubated with purified proteins or reproducible protein mixture (HPLC eluate fractions) and then irradiated with UV. The complex are treated with an enzyme to remove the unbound nucleic acid (Rnase A or Dnase I for example), washed and then analyzed by electrophoresis. The eventual complexes are identified by autoradiography. The proteins involved in the complex can be recognized by specific antibodies or by retrieving the original protein mixture and carrying further analysis on it. The affinity of the binding can be estimated by adding a non-labelled nucleic acid as competitor before the UV irradiation." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0825</id>
        <fullname>x-ray fiber diffraction</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of the diffraction pattern of a partially ordered sample composed of fibers oriented parallel to each other using X-ray." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0428</id>
        <fullname>imaging technique</fullname>
        <description>"Methods that provide images of molecules at various resolution depending on the technology used." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0969</id>
        <fullname>bio-layer interferometry</fullname>
        <description>"BLI is an optical analytical technique that analyzes the interference pattern of white light reflected from two surfaces: a layer of immobilized protein on the biosensor tip, and an internal reference layer" [PMID:19561609]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0968</id>
        <fullname>biosensor</fullname>
        <description>"A biosensor is a device for the detection of an analyte that combines a biological component with a physicochemical detector component" [PMID:10872504]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0425</id>
        <fullname>kinase scintillation proximity assay</fullname>
        <description>"Relies on the radiolabelling of a peptide substrate immobilized on a scintillant coated SPA-bead. The kinase transfers a phosphate isotope from the nucleotide to the substrate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0966</id>
        <fullname>ultraviolet-visible spectroscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Ultraviolet-visible spectroscopy or ultraviolet-visible spectrophotometry (UV-Vis or UV/Vis) involves the spectroscopy of photons in the UV-visible region. This means it uses light in the visible and adjacent (near ultraviolet (UV) and near infrared (NIR)) ranges." [PMID:18799738]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0424</id>
        <fullname>protein kinase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Catalysis of the transfer of a phosphate group, usually from ATP, to a protein substrate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0965</id>
        <fullname>2d-infrared spectrometry</fullname>
        <description>"Two-dimensional infrared correlation spectroscopy analysis is the application of 2D correlation analysis on infrared spectra. 2D IR spectroscopy probes molecular structures by means of vibrational frequencies, couplings, and transition dipole angles." [PMID:17502604]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0964</id>
        <fullname>infrared spectroscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Subset of spectroscopy that deals with the infrared region of the electromagnetic spectrum." [PMID:15212548]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0426</id>
        <fullname>light microscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Light visible microscopy uses environmental light to illuminate the sample and produce a magnified image of the sample." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0963</id>
        <fullname>interactome parallel affinity capture</fullname>
        <description>"A specific pull down method where the protein of interest (bait) is endogenously expressed with at least two affinity tags (GFP, FLAG or others). The bait is purified in parallel using different purification protocols in contrast to tandem affinity purification (TAP) (publication currently in press)." [PMID:14681455]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0420</id>
        <fullname>kinase homogeneous time resolved fluorescence</fullname>
        <description>"Measures quenching of the nonradiative energy transfer between fluorescent long-lifetime lanthanide chelates and different acceptors. Relies on a fluorescence energy donor and acceptor being added from close proximity on the phosphorylated substrate due to the action of the kinase." [PMID:14987100]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0423</id>
        <fullname>in-gel kinase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Substrate protein radio-labelled by kinase transferring an isotope of phosphate from the nucleotide. Substrate isolated by gel electrophoresis and radio-labelling confirmed by autoradiography." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0813</id>
        <fullname>proximity enzyme linked immunosorbent assay</fullname>
        <description>"Method allowing efficient and precise interaction detection, along with extensive repertoires of specific binding reagents.  It is based on proximity a ligation mechanism that enables sensitive high-capacity protein measurements by converting the detection of specific proteins to the analysis of DNA sequences. Proximity probes containing oligonucleotide extensions are designed to bind pairwise to target proteins and to form amplifiable tag sequences by ligation when brought in proximity." [PMID:15155907]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0814</id>
        <fullname>protease accessibility laddering</fullname>
        <description>"In protease accessibility laddering (PAL) tagged proteins are purified on magnetic beads in their natively folded  state. While attached to the beads, proteins are probed with proteases. Proteolytic fragments are eluted and detected by immunoblotting with antibodies against the tag (e.g., Protein A, GFP, and 6xHis)." [PMID:16615907]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0699</id>
        <fullname>rna directed dna polymerase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0697</id>
        <fullname>dna directed dna polymerase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1); the synthesis of DNA from deoxyribonucleotide triphosphates in the presence of a DNA template or primer." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0698</id>
        <fullname>dna directed rna polymerase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0695</id>
        <fullname>sandwich immunoassay</fullname>
        <description>"Antibody array where proteins retained by the arrayed antibodies are identified using a detector antibody. The detector antibody is either modified with a directly detectable label (enzyme, fluorescent molecule, isotope, etc.), or it is biotinylated for detection after subsequent probing with labeled streptavidin." [PMID:12454649]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0696</id>
        <fullname>polymerase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the transfer of a free nucleotidyl group to a nucleic acid chain." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0419</id>
        <fullname>gtpase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the reaction: GTP + H2O = GDP + phosphate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0417</id>
        <fullname>footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"footprinting analysis is used to identify regions of molecules directly involved in binding other macromolecules and therefore protected from the effects of degradative enzymes." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0416</id>
        <fullname>fluorescence microscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Fluorescent microscopy uses a high intensity light to illuminate the sample. This light excites fluorescence species in the sample, which then emit light of a longer wavelength. A fluorescent microscope also produces a magnified image of the sample, but the image is based on the second light source -- the light emanating from the fluorescent species -- rather than from the light originally used to illuminate, and excite, the sample." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0953</id>
        <fullname>polymerization</fullname>
        <description>"Interaction inferred by monitoring polymerization/depolymerization of an interactor" [PMID:19081060]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0415</id>
        <fullname>enzymatic study</fullname>
        <description>"Participants are enzyme or substrate in a biochemical reaction." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0413</id>
        <fullname>electrophoretic mobility shift assay</fullname>
        <description>"This method proves the interaction between a nucleic acid and a protein partner. On the same electrophoresis gel 1 lane is loaded with a radiolabeled nucleic acid of known sequence, a second lane is loaded with the same nucleic acid together with a purified protein (or a protein mixture). After the electrophoresis run and autoradiography by comparing the nucleic acid migration in the two lanes the retardation of the nucleic acid due to its interaction with a protein can be easily observed." [PMID:12169687]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0412</id>
        <fullname>electrophoretic mobility supershift assay</fullname>
        <description>"The EMSA supershift is a EMSA experiment carried out using a third lane loaded with the radiolabeled nucleic acid, a protein mixture and an antibody for a specific protein. If an extra retardation is observed, this is due to the formation of a larger complex including the antibody. By this approach, at least one protein of the complex is directly identified." [PMID:12169687]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0410</id>
        <fullname>electron tomography</fullname>
        <description>"Electron tomography is a general method for three-dimensional (3D) reconstruction of single, transparent objects from a series of projection images (i.e. from a tilt series) recorded with a transmission electron microscope. It offers the opportunity to obtain 3D information on structural cellular arrangements with a high resolution." [PMID:12160704]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0841</id>
        <fullname>phosphotransfer assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the rate of a phosphate transfer between two proteins" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0943</id>
        <fullname>detection by mass spectrometry</fullname>
        <description>"'Study of interactions by an analytical technique based on measurements of mass-to-charge ratio of charged particles in a mass spectrometer." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0944</id>
        <fullname>mass spectrometry study of hydrogen/deuterium exchange</fullname>
        <description>"Mass spectroscopy based measurement of the rate and/or extent of the hydrogen/deuterium exchange." [PMID:18948593]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0947</id>
        <fullname>bead aggregation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Binding of proteins bound to beads leads to a measurable aggregation of the beads." [PMID:19114658]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0946</id>
        <fullname>ping</fullname>
        <description>"Combines on-chip in-vitro protein synthesis with an in situ microfluidic affinity assay." [PMID:19098921]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0949</id>
        <fullname>gdp/gtp exchange assay</fullname>
        <description>"Experiments monitoring\ninteractions of GTP-GDP exchange factors with their cognate GTPases." [PMID:17925023]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0225</id>
        <fullname>chromatin immunoprecipitation array</fullname>
        <description>"The method combines a modified chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) procedure, with DNA microarray analysis. Cells are fixed with formaldehyde, harvested, and disrupted by sonication. The DNA fragments cross-linked to a protein of interest are enriched by immunoprecipitation with a specific antibody. After reversal of the cross-links, the enriched DNA is amplified and labeled with a fluorescent dye (Cy5) by using a ligation-mediatedpolymerase chain reaction (LM-PCR). In parallel a sample of DNA that is not enriched by immunoprecipitation is subjected to LM-PCR in the presence of a different fluorophore (Cy3), and both immunoprecipitation (IP)-enriched and unenriched pools of labeled DNA were hybridized to a single DNA microarray containing a set of intergenic sequences. The ratio of the Cy5 to Cy3 fluorescence intensities measured at each DNA element in the microarray provided a measure of the extent of binding of the transcription factor to the corresponding genomic locus." [PMID:11125145, PMID:11206552]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0441</id>
        <fullname>synthetic genetic analysis</fullname>
        <description>"Identification of genetic interactions by generation of an organism harbouring mutations in 2 or more genes and scoring for a phenotype, such as loss of viability, that is not observed for any of the mutations in isolation." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0229</id>
        <fullname>green fluorescence protein complementation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Protein-protein interaction trap based on fusions of bait and prey protein to two dissected fragment of GFP. The system implemented in E. coli, allow screening of partners, including membrane proteins and also detect transient interaction that are stabilized by the complemented GFP." [PMID:15631464]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0440</id>
        <fullname>saturation binding</fullname>
        <description>"Saturation binding experiments measure specific ligand binding at equilibrium at various concentrations of the ligand. Analysis of these data can determine receptor number and affinity." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0228</id>
        <fullname>cytoplasmic complementation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Protein complementation assay performed by dissecting a cytoplasmic protein activity and restoring it through the two hybrid proteins interaction." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0227</id>
        <fullname>reverse phase chromatography</fullname>
        <description>"Reverse phase chromatography operates on the basis of hydrophilicity and lipophilicity. The stationary phase consists of silica based packings with n-alkyl chains covalently bound. For example, C-8 signifies an octyl chain and C-18 an octadecyl ligand in the matrix. The more hydrophobic the matrix on each ligand, the greater is the tendency of the column to retain hydrophobic moieties. Thus hydrophilic compounds elute more quickly than do hydrophobic compounds." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0226</id>
        <fullname>ion exchange chromatography</fullname>
        <description>"Stable complexes and their component proteins can be separated on the basis of their net charge by ion-exchange chromatography. If a protein has a net positive charge at pH 7, it will usually bind to a column of beads containing carboxylate groups, and can then be eluted by increasing the concentration of sodium chloride or another salt in the eluting buffer by competition of sodium ions with positively charged groups on the protein for binding to the column. Protein that have a low density of net positive charge will tend to emerge first, followed by those having a higher charge density. Positively charged complexes or proteins (cationic proteins) can be separated on negatively charged carboxymethyl-cellulose (CM-cellulose) columns. Conversely, negatively charged complexes or proteins (anionic proteins) can be separated by chromatography on positively charged diethylaminoethyl-cellulose (DEAE-cellulose) columns." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0434</id>
        <fullname>phosphatase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the reaction: a phosphoprotein + H2O = a protein + phosphate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0432</id>
        <fullname>one hybrid</fullname>
        <description>"Protein-DNA complementation assay where a single promoter act as bait and is screened against a library of prey transcription factors." [PMID:10589421]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0437</id>
        <fullname>protein tri hybrid</fullname>
        <description>"Two hybrid assay performed with a third protein component co-transfected into a recombinant yeast strain together with a bait and a prey construct. Negative control shows that the interaction between the bait and the prey do not occur when the third protein is not co-transfected." [PMID:12052864, PMID:12761205, PMID:12935900]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0231</id>
        <fullname>mammalian protein protein interaction trap</fullname>
        <description>"The MAPPIT(mammalian protein-protein interaction Trap) is a screening method for protein-protein interaction in mammalian cells, based on the reconstitution of a membrane STAT (signal transducers and activators of transcription) receptor. The bait protein is fused to a STAT recruitment-deficient receptor and the prey protein to a functional STAT recruitment sites. In such a configuration, a given baitprey interaction restores a STAT-dependent responses leading to the expression of a reporter gene. This system, enable to demonstrate not only protein interaction but also modification-independent and tyrosine phosphorylation- dependent interactions." [PMID:12853652]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0438</id>
        <fullname>rna tri hybrid</fullname>
        <description>"In vivo reconstruction of specific RNA-proteins interactions. The DNA binding and transcription activator domains of GAL4 are brought together via the interaction of recombinant RNA. The first hybrid protein contains the DNA binding domain of GAL4 fused to RevM10 (a mutated RNA binding protein of HIV-1 that binds specifically to the Rev responsive element RRE of the env gene). A recombinant RNA contains the RRE sequence and a target RNA sequence X. The second hybrid protein contains the activation domain of GAL4 fused to protein Y tested for its ability to bind the target RNA X. If this interaction occurs the three hybrid reconstructs GAL4 and the transcription of a reporter gene is activated." [PMID:12162957, PMID:8972875]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0232</id>
        <fullname>transcriptional complementation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Protein complementation assay performed by dissecting a transcription factor activity (DNA binding domain and transcription activation domain) its restoration through the two hybrid proteins interaction that lead to a reporter gene expression." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0435</id>
        <fullname>protease assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the enzymatic hydrolysis of a peptide bond within a peptide or protein substrate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0230</id>
        <fullname>membrane bound complementation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Protein complementation assay based on dissection of a membrane protein." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0439</id>
        <fullname>random spore analysis</fullname>
        <description>"A technique used to detect genetic interactions between 2 (or more) genes in a sporulating organism by scoring a large population of haploid spores for a phenotype and correlating the phenotype with the presence of single vs double (multiple) mutations. A diploid heterozygous organism harbouring mutations in two (or more) genes is induced to sporulate. Resulting spores are meiotic segregants that are haploid and are either wild type or mutant at each locus. Spores are scored for a phenotype, such as loss of viability." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0938</id>
        <fullname>rheology measurement</fullname>
        <description>"Characterization of viscoelastic properties of biomolecule solution is used to infer interactions between molecules." [PMID:18445655]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0729</id>
        <fullname>luminescence based mammalian interactome mapping</fullname>
        <description>"This strategy uses Renilla luciferase enzyme (RL) fused to proteins of interest, which are then coexpressed with individual Flag-tagged partners in mammalian cells. Their interactions are determined by performing an RL enzymatic assay on anti-Flag immunoprecipitates." [PMID:15761153]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0728</id>
        <fullname>gal4 vp16 complementation</fullname>
        <description>"A chimeric protein consisting of the GAL4 DNA-binding domain (aa 1-147 of GAL4) and a transcriptional activation domain from the herpes simplex virus protein VP16 (either aa 411-490 or aa 411-455) can specifically activate transcription of a reporter gene located downstream ofGAL4 DNA binding sites and the E1B minimal promoter. Similarly, two chimeric proteins, one encoding a chimeric GAL4 protein and the other encoding a chimeric VP16 protein, can activate the reporter gene, if the domains fused to the GAL4 and VP16 sequences can complex with appropriate conformation. However, if the domains fused to the GAL4 and VP16 sequences do not interact specifically to form a + complex that reconstitutes GAL4 function, the reporter gene cannot be activated." [PMID:1387709]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0727</id>
        <fullname>lexa b52 complementation</fullname>
        <description>"Yeast two-hybrid system using Escherichia coli LexA amino acids 1-202 as the DNA-binding domain (BD), E. coli B42 acidic sequence as the activation domain (AD), and two reporters, lacZ and LEU2, each containing upstream LexA binding elements." [PMID:14613974]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0726</id>
        <fullname>reverse two hybrid</fullname>
        <description>"Yeast strains are generated in which expression of DB-X/AD-Y or DBPX hybrid proteins is toxic under particular conditions (negative selection). Under these conditions, dissociation of an interaction should provide a selective advantage thereby facilitating detection: a few growing yeast colonies in which DB-X/AD-Y (or DBPX/binding site) fail to interact should be identified among many nongrowing colonies containing interacting DB-X/AD-Y or DBPX/binding site." [PMID:8816797]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0663</id>
        <fullname>confocal microscopy</fullname>
        <description>"A confocal is a standard epifluorescence microscope with improvement essentially coming from the rejection of out-of-focus light interference. Confocal imaging system achieves this by two strategies: a) by illuminating a single point of the specimen at any one time with a focused beam, so that illumination intensity drops off rapidly and b) by the use of blocking a pinhole aperture in a conjugate focal plane to the specimen so that light emitted away from the point in the specimen being illuminated is blocked from reaching the detector. Only the light from the single point illuminated of the specimen passing through the image pinhole is detected by a photodetector. Usually a computer is used to control the sequential scanning of the sample and to assemble the image for display onto a video screen." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0921</id>
        <fullname>surface plasmon resonance array</fullname>
        <description>"This array technology allows the screening of binding abilities of hundreds or thousands of biomolecules (small molecule, peptide, protein, sugar, lipid, nucleic acid, and their fragments) printed onto the gold-coated chip by using an instrument (micro-arrayer) that is capable of spotting liquid samples in a reproducible manner onto a planar support. The ordered protein array can then be probed with a non-labelled sample (small molecule, peptide, protein, sugar, lipid, nucleic acid, and their fragments) to identify the baits that can bind to it.  This is done in real time, allowing direct measurement of both the on-rate and the off-rate and of the affinity constant of complex formation on each spot." [PMID:16510109, PMID:16837183, PMID:17889820]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0920</id>
        <fullname>ribonuclease assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the hydrolysis of phosphodiester bonds in chains of RNA." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0928</id>
        <fullname>filter trap assay</fullname>
        <description>"Biomolecules are mixed in a buffer and the resulting mixture is\npassed through a filter. Large\naggregates are retained on the filter and the pariticipants may then be identified." [PMID:10859365]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0870</id>
        <fullname>demethylase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the hydrolysis of an methyl group from a substrate molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0100</id>
        <fullname>sequence based phylogenetic profile</fullname>
        <description>"Multiple alignments of orthologous sequences in the same species and their corresponding phylogenetic trees are built. Every phylogenetic tree is computed as a matrix of distances between all possible protein pairs. The covariation of the distance matrices reveals interacting protein pairs." [PMID:11707606]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0104</id>
        <fullname>static light scattering</fullname>
        <description>"In static light scattering, the average intensity of scattered light at multiple angles is measured. The data yield information on particle molecular weight, particle size and shape, and particle-particle interactions." [PMID:9013660]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0511</id>
        <fullname>protease homogeneous time resolved fluorescence</fullname>
        <description>"Measures quenching of the nonradiative energy transfer between fluorescent long-lifetime lanthanide chelates and different acceptors. Fluorescence donor and acceptor are on the same peptide molecule and separated by the action of the protease." [PMID:14987100]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0510</id>
        <fullname>homogeneous time resolved fluorescence</fullname>
        <description>"Methods based on the exceptionally long fluorescence lifetime characteristics of certain fluorophores, which allows the elimination of the effects of background fluorescence. Uses nonradiative energy transfer or quenching between fluorescent lanthanide chelates and different acceptors to measure reaction rates." [PMID:14987100]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0101</id>
        <fullname>sequence based prediction</fullname>
        <description>"Computational methods based on evolutionary hypothesis, used as criteria to browse sequences and predict interacting pairs." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0108</id>
        <fullname>t7 phage display</fullname>
        <description>"T7 is a double stranded DNA bacteriophage with a thin-walled icosahedral capsid, ~550 Angstrom in diameter, which is decorated by 415 copies of the capsid protein, the product of gene 10. gp10 can tolerate insertions at the carboxyterminus without loosing its ability to be inserted into functional phage capsids. Both low density and high density display (albeit only with short peptides) can be achieved." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0515</id>
        <fullname>methyltransferase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the transfer of a methyl group to an acceptor molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0107</id>
        <fullname>surface plasmon resonance</fullname>
        <description>"This method measures formation of complex by monitoring changes in the resonance angle of light impinging on a gold surface as a result of changes in the refractive index of the surface. A ligand of interest (small molecule, peptide, protein, sugar, lipid, nucleic acid) is immobilized on a gold surface, and the interacting partner is injected in buffer flow over it. Biomolecules that interact with the immobilized ligand are retained on the surface, and alter the resonance angle of impinging light as a result of the change in refractive index brought about by the increased biomolecule mass retained on the surface. Since all the biomolecules belonging to the same class have the same refractive index and since there is a linear correlation between resonance angle shift and biomolecule concentration near the surface, this allows one to measure changes in concentration at the surface as a consequence of interaction. Furthermore, this is done in real time, allowing direct measurement of both the on-rate and the off-rate and of the affinity constant of complex formation." [PMID:11896282, PMID:12120258, PMID:16338355]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0514</id>
        <fullname>in gel phosphatase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Substrate protein pre-radiolabelled either synthetically or through the action of a kinase transferring an isotope of phosphate from a nucleotide. Substrate then exposed to phosphate under assay conditions. Substrate isolated by gel electrophoresis and loss of radiolabelling confirmed by autoradiography." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0513</id>
        <fullname>collagen film assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the amount of radiolabel released into the medium when enzyme is added onto a film of isotope-labelled collagen." [PMID:6247938]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0105</id>
        <fullname>structure based prediction</fullname>
        <description>"Methods based on 3D structure information." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0512</id>
        <fullname>zymography</fullname>
        <description>"Samples run on a gelatine containing gels under non-reducing condition, gels then incubated under conditions in which the enzyme is active. Gels are stained with coomasie and gelatine-free regions of the gel taken as a measure of enzyme activity." [PMID:2071592]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0858</id>
        <fullname>immunodepleted coimmunoprecipitation</fullname>
        <description>"Method involving consecutive coimmunoimmunoprecipitations on the same sample, a control  where an interaction is detected, and other CoIPs where the sample is previously treated with a specific antibody that precipitates a candidate interactor and leads to the suppression of an interaction or a change in composition of a complex." [PMID:17081976]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0657</id>
        <fullname>systematic evolution of ligands by exponential enrichment</fullname>
        <description>"RNA and cDNA constructs with variable central sequences and a constant flanking region are collected in a complex library. The library is then screened to select either specific binding partners of a bait molecule (generally a protein) or particular enzymatic activities of the nucleic acid molecules themselves. The selected nucleic acids are amplified using the constant flanking regions to increase their abundance. Cycles of selection-amplification can be repeated to increase the specificity of the targets that, at the end, are individually identified by sequencing." [PMID:11539574]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0655</id>
        <fullname>lambda repressor two hybrid</fullname>
        <description>"A protein of interest (the bait) is fused to the full-length bacteriophage lambda repressor protein (lambdacI, 237 amino acids), containing the amino terminal DNA-binding domain and the carboxylterminal dimerization domain. The corresponding target (prey) protein is fused to the N-terminal domain of the alfa-subunit of RNA polymerase (248 amino acids). The bait is tethered to the lambda operator sequence upstream of the reporter promoter through the DNA-binding domain of lambdacI. When the bait and prey interact, they recruit and stabilize the binding of RNA polymerase at the promoter and activate the transcription of the HIS3 reporter gene. Due to the tendency of both the lambda repressor protein and the N-terminal domain of the alfa-subunit of RNA polymerase to dimerize, this system might not be optimal for the analysis of proteins that self-associate unless their interaction with other protein partners depends on the oligomerization." [PMID:15792953]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0859</id>
        <fullname>intermolecular force</fullname>
        <description>"An optical tweezer is a scientific instrument that uses a focused laser beam to provide an attractive or repulsive force, depending on the index mismatch (typically on the order of piconewtons) to physically hold and move microscopic dielectric objects (i.e.highly resistants to the flow of an electric current). This instrument allow to measure the forces generated between interacting molecules - either at the level of just single interacting pair of molecules or at the level of larger molecular assemblies. " [PMID:17023539, PMID:17081984]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0516</id>
        <fullname>methyltransferase radiometric assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the transfer of a radiolabelled methyl group of a donor, for example S-adenosyl-L-methionine (SAM) to a carboxyl group of an acceptor." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0916</id>
        <fullname>lexa vp16 complementation</fullname>
        <description>"Yeast two-hybrid system using Escherichia coli LexA amino acids 1-202 as the DNA-binding domain (BD), and a transcriptional activation domain from the herpes simplex virus protein VP16 (either aa 411-490 or aa 411-455) that can specifically activate transcription of a reporter gene located downstream." [PMID:9371806]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0110</id>
        <fullname>text mining</fullname>
        <description>"Text mining methods can be used to predict or confirm interactions by automated processing of scientific literature. Co-occurrence in the same sentence of an abstract of gene products labels are analysed to evaluate whether it represents a valid evidence of an interaction." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0111</id>
        <fullname>dihydrofolate reductase reconstruction</fullname>
        <description>"The gene for DHFR is rationally dissected into two fragments called F[1,2] and F[3]. Two proteins or protein domains that are thought to bind to each other can then be fused to either of the two DHFR fragments. Reconstitution of enzyme activity can be monitored in vivo by cell survival in DHFR-negative cells grown in the absence of nucleotides. A fluorescence assay can also be carried out taking advantage of fMTX binding to reconstituted DHFR. The basis of this assay is that complementary fragments of DHFR, when expressed and reassembled in cells, will bind with high affinity (Kd 5 540 pM) to fMTX in a 1:1 complex. fMTX is retained in cells by this complex, whereas the unbound fMTX is actively and rapidly transported out of the cells. Survival depends only on the number of molecules of DHFR reassembled." [PMID:10318894]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0901</id>
        <fullname>isotope label footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"Exposed amino acid residues undergo a rapid exchange of a specific radio-isotope e.g. hydrogen/deuterium. Residues involved in a molecular interaction are protected from this exchange and exhibit a much slower rate of exchange. This method of binding range identification must be coupled to NMR or mass spectrometry  technologies in order to detect the radio-isotope exchange." [PMID:18184591]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0880</id>
        <fullname>atpase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the hydrolisis of ATP+ H2O = ADP + phosphate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0905</id>
        <fullname>amplified luminescent proximity homogeneous assay</fullname>
        <description>"AlphaScreen relies on the use of Donor and Acceptor beads that are coated with a layer of hydrogel providing functional groups for bioconjugation. When a biological interaction between molecules brings the beads into proximity, a cascade of chemical reactions is initiated to produce a greatly amplified signal. Upon laser excitation, a photosensitizer in the Donor bead converts ambient oxygen to a more excited singlet state. The singlet state oxygen molecules diffuse across to react with a chemiluminescer in the Acceptor bead that further activates fluorophores contained within the same bead. The fluorophores subsequently emit light at 520-620 nm. In the absence of a specific biological interaction, the singlet state oxygen molecules produced by the Donor bead go undetected without the close proximity of the Acceptor bead. AlphaScreen has successfully been developed for enzyme assays (kinase, helicase, protease, ...), interaction assays (ligand/receptor, protein/protein, protein/DNA), immunoassays, and GPCR functional assays (cAMP, IP3)." [PMID:17092917]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0058</id>
        <fullname>genome based prediction</fullname>
        <description>"Methods that require fully sequenced genomes either because they are based on the comparison of genome topology or on the identification of orthologous sequences in different genomes." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0057</id>
        <fullname>gene neighbourhood</fullname>
        <description>"Gene pairs that show a conserved topological neighbourhood in many prokaryotic genomes are considered by this approach to encode interacting or functionally related proteins. By measuring the physical distance of any given gene pair in different genomes, interacting partners are inferred." [PMID:9787636]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>IMPD</id>
        <fullname>Imported</fullname>
        <description>Imported</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0900</id>
        <fullname>p8 filamentous phage display</fullname>
        <description>"pVIII is the major coat protein of filamentous phage. Its amino-terminus is exposed to solvent and tolerates the insertion of relatively large peptide fragments. By inserting the peptide coding sequence into the phage copy of the pVIII gene up to 3000 copies of the hybrid proteins can be displayed along the phage capsid. Alternatively the hybrid protein can be encoded on a phagemid that is incorporated in a virus like particle by infection with a helper phage. In this latter case one obtains a chimeric capsid where hybrid proteins are interspersed at different density in an otherwise wild type coat. Because of the high copy number pVIII display is also referred to as high valency display." [PMID:1720463]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0257</id>
        <fullname>antisense rna</fullname>
        <description>"This approach is based on the observation that expression of RNA that is complementary to a specific mRNA can decrease the synthesis of its gene product either by increasing the degradation of the targeted mRNA or by interfering with its translation." [PMID:1340158]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0063</id>
        <fullname>interaction prediction</fullname>
        <description>"Computational methods to predict an interaction." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0879</id>
        <fullname>nucleoside triphosphatase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the hydrolisis of a  nucleoside triphosphate into a nucleoside diphosphate plus phosphate." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0255</id>
        <fullname>post transcriptional interference</fullname>
        <description>"This term refers to methods designed to interfere with gene expression at post-transcriptional level rather than with the gene itself." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0256</id>
        <fullname>rna interference</fullname>
        <description>"RNA interference (RNAi) is a post-transcriptional gene silencing method reproducing a naturally occurring phenomena. RNAi is the process whereby double-stranded RNA (dsRNA) induces the sequence-specific degradation of homologous mRNA. RNAi or dsRNA-induced silencing phenomena are present in evolutionarily diverse organisms, e.g., nematodes, plants, fungi, and trypanosomes. The mechanisms by which RNAi works is initiated by a progressive cleavage of dsRNA into 21 to 23 nucleotide (nt) short interfering RNAs (siRNAs). These native siRNA duplexes are then incorporated into a protein complex called RNA-induced silencing complex (RISC). ATP-dependent unwinding of the siRNA duplex generates an active RISC complex. Guided by the antisense strand of siRNA, the active RISC complex recognizes and cleaves the corresponding mRNA." [PMID:12110901, PMID:12408823]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0066</id>
        <fullname>lambda phage display</fullname>
        <description>"Morphologically classified as one of the siphoviridae, lambda is a temperate bacteriophage of E.coli, with a double-stranded DNA genome. It has an icosahedral head attached to a flexible helical tail. Both the tail protein pV and the head protein pD have been used for displaying (C or N terminally) foreign peptides on the viral capsid." [PMID:7682645]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0067</id>
        <fullname>light scattering</fullname>
        <description>"Dynamic and static laser light scattering probes the size, shape, and structure of biological macromolecules or of their assemblies. A beam is focused on an optically clear cylindrical cell containing the sample. Most of the light passes directly through the sample. A small portion of the light is scattered; the scattered light intensity containing information about the scattering particle is detected at an angle (typically in the range 15-180degrees) from the direction of the incident beam." [PMID:9013660]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0064</id>
        <fullname>interologs mapping</fullname>
        <description>"Protein interactions, experimentally detected in an organism, are extended to a second organism assuming that homologue proteins, in different organisms, maintain their interaction properties." [PMID:11731503]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0065</id>
        <fullname>isothermal titration calorimetry</fullname>
        <description>"Isothermal titration calorimetry (ITC) measures directly the energy associated with a chemical reaction triggered by the mixing of two components. A typical ITC experiment is carried out by the stepwise addition of one of the reactants (~10-6 L per injection) into the reaction cell (~1mL) containing the second reactant. The chemical reaction occurring after each injection either releases or absorbs heat (qi) proportional to the amount of ligand that binds to the protein with a characteristic binding enthalpy (DH). As modern ITC instruments operate on the heat compensation principle, the instrumental response (measured signal) is the amount of power (microcalories per second) necessary to maintain constant the temperature difference between the reaction and the reference cells. Because the amount of uncomplexed protein available progressively decreases after each successive injection, the magnitude of the peaks becomes progressively smaller until complete saturation is achieved. The difference between the concentration of bound ligand in the ith and (i-1)th injections depends on the binding constant Ka and the total ligand injected. The calculations depend on the binding model (number of substrates). Analysis of the data yields DH and DG = -RTlnKa. The entropy change is obtained by using the standard thermodynamic expression DG = DH-TDS." [PMID:11785756]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0397</id>
        <fullname>two hybrid array</fullname>
        <description>"Two-hybrid screening can be done in a colony array format, in which each colony expresses a defined pair of proteins. Because the particular protein pair expressed in each colony is defined by its position in the array, positive signals identify interacting proteins without further characterization, thus obviating the need for DNA purification and sequencing. The interrogation of a two-hybrid colony array usually involves a mating strategy in which every DNA binding domain hybrid (the bait) is tested against all activation domain hybrids (the preys) in a grid pattern. Arrays usually use full-length open reading frames." [PMID:11827624, PMID for application instance:10688190]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0872</id>
        <fullname>atomic force microscopy</fullname>
        <description>"The atomic force microscope (AFM) is a very high-resolution type of scanning probe microscope, with demonstrated resolution of fractions of a nanometer, more than 1000 times better than the optical diffraction limit. The AFM was invented by Binnig, Quate and Gerber in 1986, and is one of the foremost tools for imaging, measuring and manipulating matter at the nanoscale.The term 'microscope' in the name is actually a misnomer because it implies looking, while in fact the information is gathered by feeling out the surface with a mechanical feeler.\nhttp://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atomic_force_microscope" [PMID:17502105]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0114</id>
        <fullname>x-ray crystallography</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of a diffraction pattern generated by a single crystal. X-rays have a wavelength, typically around 1 Angstrom (the diameter of a hydrogen atom). If a narrow parallel beam of X-rays is directed at a sample of a pure protein, most of the X-rays will pass straight through it. A small fraction, however, will be scattered by the atoms in the sample. If the sample is a well-ordered crystal, the scattered waves will reinforce one another at certain points and will appear as diffraction spots when the X-rays are recorded by a suitable detector. The position and intensity of each spot in the X-ray diffraction pattern contain information about the position and nature of the atoms in the crystal. The three-dimensional structure of a large molecule can be deduced from the electron-density map of its crystal. In recent years X-ray diffraction analysis has become increasingly automated, and now the slowest step is likely to be the production of suitable macromolecule crystals. This requires high concentration of very pure macromolecule and empirical searching for the proper crystallisation conditions." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0115</id>
        <fullname>yeast display</fullname>
        <description>"The proteins are displayed on the surface of the yeast S. cerevisiae by fusion to signal sequences for protein secretion. This method is limited by the low efficiency of the yeast display system but can take full advantage of exploiting cell sorting methods (FACS) to isolate cells that display molecules with desired binding properties." [PMID:9181578]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0112</id>
        <fullname>ubiquitin reconstruction</fullname>
        <description>"In this method the two proteins, whose interaction is under investigation, (in this case mostly membrane proteins) are fused to an terminal fragment (Nub) and to a C-terminal fragment of ubiquitin (Cub). The two fragments do not associate to form a functional ubiquitin unless the two fused membrane proteins form a complex. The association is monitored by an ingenious trick. The C-term fragment of ubiquitin is expressed as a fusion to a transcription factor that being linked to a membrane protein cannot perform its function unless it is released form the ubiquitin fusion by a specific protease. This achieved through the activity of UBP (an ubiquitin specific protease) that cleaves off the reporter protein only when a functional ubiquitin is reconstituted." [PMID:9560251]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0892</id>
        <fullname>solid phase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Assay where at least one molecule under analysis is bound to a solid surface, such as a microplate wall or the sides of a tube, the other reactants being free in solution." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0891</id>
        <fullname>neutron fiber diffraction</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of diffraction pattern of a partially ordered sample composed of fibers oriented parallel to each other using neutron beam." [PMID:10771422, PMID:15272083, PMID:15546977, PMID:15914673, PMID:16041074, PMID:16707576]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0069</id>
        <fullname>mass spectrometry studies of complexes</fullname>
        <description>"Mass spectrometric approaches to the study of protein in complexes permits the identification of subunit stoichiometry and transient associations. By preserving complexes intact in the mass spectrometer, mass measurement can be used for monitoring changes in different experimental conditions, or to investigate how variations of collision energy affect their dissociation." [PMID:12504676, PMID for application instance:12057199]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0276</id>
        <fullname>blue native page</fullname>
        <description>"Blue native PAGE (BN-PAGE) permits a high-resolution separation of multi-protein complexes under native conditions. Blue native (BN)-PAGE is a charge shift method, in which the electrophoretic mobility of a complex is determined by the negative charge of the bound Coomassie dye and the size and shape of the complex. Coomassie does not act as a detergent and preserves the structure of complexes. Importantly, the resolution of BN-PAGE is much higher than that of other methods such as gel filtration or sucrose-gradient ultracentrifugation. Combined with other pre-purifications or dialysis steps this method permits the analysis of multi-protein complexes of whole cellular lysates by BN-PAGE." [PMID:14665681]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0602</id>
        <fullname>chemical footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"Binding sites are identified by altered reactivity of a complex to a chemical treatment compared to the unbound molecules. Residues in close contact with the binding partner are protected from cleavage by the enzyme. When these chemicals are administrated to intact cells, the pattern of protection from the probes identifies the location of DNA-protein or protein-protein interactions in vivo." [PMID:8238889]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0071</id>
        <fullname>molecular sieving</fullname>
        <description>"In sizing columns (gel filtration), the elution position of a protein or of a complex depends on its Stokes radius. Molecules with a radius that is smaller than the bead size are retained and retarded by the interaction with the matrix. The observation that two proteins, loaded on a sieving column, elute in a fraction(s) corresponding to a MW that is larger than the MW of either protein may be taken as an indication that the two proteins interact. Furthermore this technique provides a conceptually simple method for evaluating the affinity of the interaction." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0603</id>
        <fullname>dimethylsulphate footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"Dimethylsulphate (DMS) is the most commonly used chemical to study DNA-protein interactions. DMS induces methylation of guanine residues so DNA interaction with protein binding to AT rich sequences or to the phosphate backbone may be not detected by DMS footprinting. However as DMS diffuses across membrane it can also be used for in vivo footprinting. The experiment involves the treatment with DMS of two DNA samples with identical sequence, one protein bound and the other naked. The two samples are treated with piperidine to induce chemical cleavage of the DMS modified guanine residues followed by digestion with restriction enzymes. Once labelled the samples are run in parallel on a gel to visualize the pattern of nested fragments sharing a common end generated by restriction enzyme(or PCR primer extension) and a variable end guanine dependent. The missing bands of the protein bound sample correspond to the guanine residues protected from modification by an interaction." [PMID:8238889]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0508</id>
        <fullname>deacetylase radiometric assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the release of radiolabelled acetic acid from pre-labeled histone." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0073</id>
        <fullname>mrna display</fullname>
        <description>"This method relies on the covalent coupling of mRNA to the nascent polypeptide. The mRNA (natural or artificial) is first covalently linked to a short DNA linker carrying a puromycin moiety. The mRNA mixture is then translated in vitro. When the ribosome reaches the RNA-DNA junction the ribosome stalls and the puromycin moiety enters the peptidyltransferase site of the ribosome and forms a covalent linkage to the nascent polypeptide. As a result the protein and the mRNA are covalently joined and can be isolated from the ribosome and purified. In the current protocol, a cDNA strand is then synthesised to form a less sticky RNA-DNA hybrid and these complexes are finally used for affinity selection. As in most display approaches, several selections cycles (3-6) are sufficient to enrich for mRNAs encoding ligand proteins." [PMID:11551470]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0077</id>
        <fullname>nuclear magnetic resonance</fullname>
        <description>"NMR requires a small volume of concentrated compound solution that is placed in a strong magnetic field. Certain atomic nuclei, and in particular hydrogen, have a magnetic moment or spin; that is, they have an intrinsic magnetisation, like a bar magnet. The spin aligns along the strong magnetic field, but can be changed to a misaligned excited state in response to applied radio frequency (RF) pulses of electromagnetic radiation. When the excited hydrogen nuclei relax to their aligned state, they emit RF radiation, which can be measured and displayed as a spectrum. The nature of the emitted radiation depends on the environment of each hydrogen nucleus, and if one nucleus is excited, it will influence the absorption and emission of radiation by other nuclei that lie close to it. It is consequently possible, by an ingenious elaboration of the basic NMR technique known as two-dimensional NMR, to distinguish the signals from hydrogen nuclei in different amino acid residues and to identify and measure the small shifts in these signals that occur when these hydrogen nuclei lie close enough to interact: the size of such a shift reveals the distance between the interacting pair of hydrogen atoms. In this way NMR can give information about the distances between the parts of the interacting molecule. NMR provides information about interacting atoms thereby permitting to obtain information about macromolecular structure and molecular interactions." [PMID:12120505, PMID for application instance:12062432]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0509</id>
        <fullname>phosphatase homogeneous time resolved fluorescence</fullname>
        <description>"Measures quenching of the nonradiative energy transfer between fluorescent long-lifetime lanthanide chelates and different acceptors. Relies on a fluorescence energy donor and acceptor being removed from close proximity on the phosphorylated substrate due to the action of the phosphatase." [PMID:14987100]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0606</id>
        <fullname>DNase I footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"Deoxyribonuclease I (DNase I) do not have high specificity for given sequences or residues, thus footprinting with DNase I permits the exact delineation of the protein-DNA binding site. Moreover DNase I, can be used for in vivo footprinting by treating intact cells with permeabilising drugs. In this latter case DNase I in vivo footprinting allow studies of the chromatin structure in genomic DNA." [PMID:8238889]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0887</id>
        <fullname>histone acetylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"In histone acetylation the histones are acetylated on lysine residues in the N-terminal tail as part of gene regulation. Typically, these reactions are catalyzed by enzymes with \"histone acetyltransferase\" (HAt)" [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0888</id>
        <fullname>small angle neutron scattering</fullname>
        <description>"During a SANS experiment a beam of neutrons is directed at a sample. The neutrons are elastically scattered by a sample and the resulting scattering pattern is analyzed to provide information about the size, shape and orientation of some component of the sample." [PMID:11578931]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0604</id>
        <fullname>potassium permanganate footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"Potassium permanganate bind to single-stranded pyrimidine residues, it is commonly used to detect promoters opening regions in vivo. KMnO4 treatment of cells, followed by treatment with piperidine, followed by either PCR and/or acrylamide gel electrophoresis allows detection of interaction between transcription factor and the DNA sequence under their control." [PMID:8238889]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0889</id>
        <fullname>acetylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the catalysis of the addition of an acetyl group to a target molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0605</id>
        <fullname>enzymatic footprinting</fullname>
        <description>"Binding sites are identified by altered reactivity of a complex to an enzymatic probe compared to the unbound molecules. Residues in close contact with the binding partner are protected from cleavage by the enzyme. When these enzymes are administrated to intact cells, the pattern of protection from the probes identifies the location of DNA-protein or protein-protein interactions in vivo." [PMID:8238889]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0369</id>
        <fullname>lex-a dimerization assay</fullname>
        <description>"The method is based on the repression of a reporter gene activity by two LexA DNA binding domains with different binding specificities. LexA is a transcription factor with an N-terminal DNA binding/activation domain (DBAct) and a C-terminal dimerization domain. LexA dimerization is required to repress transcription efficiently. The discovery of LexA DNA binding domains that bind to different DNA sequence enabled the development of this system." [PMID:12446730]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0038</id>
        <fullname>dynamic light scattering</fullname>
        <description>"In dynamic light scattering, particle diffusion in solution gives rise to fluctuations in the intensity of the scattered light on the microsecond scale. The hydrodynamic radius of the particles can be easily calculated." [PMID:9013660]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1000</id>
        <fullname>hydroxylase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the irreversible introduction of a hydroxyl group that can affect K,P,Y or R residues." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0037</id>
        <fullname>domain profile pairs</fullname>
        <description>"This approach uses a protein interaction network of a given organism to infer interaction in another organism using information about the interacting region. The regions or domains involved in interactions are clustered if they share sequence similarity and have common interacting partners. The resulting domain profiles are then used to screen the proteome of another organism and domain-domain interactions are inferred. Ultimately, an inferred protein interaction map is built in this second organism." [PMID:11473021]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1001</id>
        <fullname>lipidation assay</fullname>
        <description>"The covalent binding of a lipid group to a peptide chain." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0036</id>
        <fullname>domain fusion</fullname>
        <description>"The rosetta stone, or domain fusion procedure, is based on the assumption that proteins whose homologues in other organisms happen to be fused into a single protein chain are likely to interact or to be functionally related." [PMID:10573422]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1002</id>
        <fullname>myristoylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the irreversible covalent addition of a myristoyl group via an amide bond to the alpha-amino group of an amino acid." [PMID:14707621]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0035</id>
        <fullname>docking</fullname>
        <description>"Predicts the structure of a molecular complex from the unbound structures of its components. The initial approach in the majority of docking procedures is based largely on the 'rigid-body' assumption, whereby the proteins are treated as solid objects. Initial scoring of a complex is based on geometric fit or surface complementarity. This generally requires some knowledge of the binding site to limit the number of solutions." [PMID:9631301, PMID for application instance:11478868]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0045</id>
        <fullname>experimental interaction detection</fullname>
        <description>"Methods based on laboratory experiments to determine an interaction." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0042</id>
        <fullname>electron paramagnetic resonance</fullname>
        <description>"EPR (also called ESR, Electron Spin Resonance) spectroscopy is analogous to NMR, but is based on the excitation of unpaired electrons instead of nuclei. Unpaired (single) electrons are only found in radicals and some metal ions (paramagnetic species); the EPR spectrum provides information about the environment and mobility of the paramagnetic species. The magnetic interaction of two paramagnetic centres in a protein can be used to calculate the distance between them; this allows studies of the movements and interactions of protein segments. In proteins without any intrinsic unpaired electrons it is possible to attach a radical probe (spin label). Stable nitroxide radicals can be bound to amino acid residues, in analogy with fluorescent probes. In combination with site directed mutagenesis this method is used in particular to study structure and assembly of membrane proteins, by measuring with EPR whether an amino acid is in a polar or non polar environment." [PMID:11817959]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0043</id>
        <fullname>electron resonance</fullname>
        <description>"A form of spectroscopy in which the absorption of microwave by a sample in a strong magnetic field is used to study atoms or molecules with unpaired electrons." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0040</id>
        <fullname>electron microscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Electron microscopy methods provide insights into the structure of biological macromolecules and their supramolecular assemblies. Resolution is on average around 10 Angstroms but can reach the atomic level when the samples analysed are 2D crystals. Different types of samples can be analysed by electron microscopy: crystals, single particles like viruses, macromolecular complexes or entire cells and tissue sections. Samples can be chemically fixed or vitrified by rapid freezing in liquid ethane, and then transferred into the electron microscope. Data collection consists of the recording of electron diffraction data (2D crystals) and images. Depending on the type of sample, different approaches are used to analyse and merge images and electron diffraction data." [PMID:11785754]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0041</id>
        <fullname>electron nuclear double resonance</fullname>
        <description>"A combination of NMR and EPR. The lines in the EPR spectrum that are caused by coupling of an unpaired electron nearby nuclei change in intensity when these nuclei are excited at their NMR frequency." [PMID:11817959, PMID:11988476, PMID for application instance:12186859]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0899</id>
        <fullname>p3 filamentous phage display</fullname>
        <description>"pIII is one of the minor coat proteins that decorates in five copies the emerging tip of filamentous phage. Similarly to pVIII pIII also tolerates peptide insertions at the amino-terminus. The sequences to be displayed can either be encoded in the phage copy of the coat gene or in an extra pIII gene copy carried on a phagemid. In the first case 5 copies o the hybrid proteins are displayed while in the latter only a few capsid display one copy and the majority display none.  Because of the low copy number pIII display is often referred to as low valency display." [PMID:1696028]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0370</id>
        <fullname>tox-r dimerization assay</fullname>
        <description>"This assay allow identification of interactions in the inner membrane of E. coli. by using a chimeric construct ToxR-TM-MBP composed of the N-terminal DNA binding/transcriptional activation domain of ToxR (a dimerization dependant transcription factor) fused to a transmembrane domain of interest (TM) and a monomeric periplasmic anchor (the maltose binding protein). Association of the two TM results in the ToxR-mediated activation of a reporter gene such as CAT (chloroamphenicol acetyltransferase activity). The level of CAT expression indicates the strength of TM association. CAT expression can then be tested and quantify by measuring CAM resistance with disk diffusion assay or CAT activity assays on cell-free extracts." [PMID:9927659]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0895</id>
        <fullname>protein kinase A complementation</fullname>
        <description>"This method uses Renilla luciferase (Rluc)-based protein fragment complementation assay (PCA) that is designed specifically to investigate dynamic protein complexes (association and dissociation). It is chose to generate a PCA based on the Rluc, which is, because of its simplicity and sensitivity, a widely used bioluminescence reporter. The general scheme for construction and detection of the Rluc-PCA PKA sensor consists of fusing complementary fragments of Rluc to the regulatory (Reg) and catalytic (Cat) PKA subunits of PKA." [PMID:17942691]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0893</id>
        <fullname>neutron diffraction</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of diffraction pattern using neutron beam" [PMID:10771422, PMID:15272083, PMID:15546977, PMID:15914673, PMID:16041074, PMID:16707576]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0894</id>
        <fullname>electron diffraction</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of diffraction pattern using electron beam." [PMID:10949309, PMID:11034202, PMID:11171962, PMID:11532455, PMID:11700061, PMID:15141214, PMID:16325200]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0254</id>
        <fullname>genetic interference</fullname>
        <description>"This term refers to methods that aim at interfering with the activity of a specific gene by altering the gene regulatory or coding sequences. This goal can be achieved either by a classical genetic approach (random mutagenesis followed by phenotype characterization and genetic mapping) or by a reverse genetics approach where a gene of interest is modified by directed mutagenesis." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0047</id>
        <fullname>far western blotting</fullname>
        <description>"Proteins are fractionated by PAGE (SDS-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis), transferred to a nitrocellulose membrane and tested for the ability to bind to a protein, a peptide, or any other ligand. Cell lysates can also be fractionated before gel electrophoresis to increase the sensitivity of the method for detecting interactions with rare proteins. Denaturants are removed during the blotting procedure, which allows many proteins to recover (or partially recover) activity. However, if biological activity is not recoverable, the proteins can be fractionated by a non denaturing gel system. This variation of the method eliminates the problem of activity regeneration and allows the detection of binding when the presence of a protein complex is required for binding. The protein probe can be prepared by any one of several procedures, while fusion affinity tags greatly facilitate purification. Synthesis in E. coli with a GST fusion, epitope tag, or other affinity tag is most commonly used. The protein of interest can then be radioactively labelled, biotinylated, or used in the blotting procedure as an unlabeled probe that is detected by a specific antibody." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0046</id>
        <fullname>experimental knowledge based</fullname>
        <description>"Predictive algorithms that rely on the information obtained by experimental results." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0049</id>
        <fullname>filter binding</fullname>
        <description>"A method in which separation depends upon the ability of one participant to bind to a filter or membrane which the other participants do not. Molecules interacting with the bound molecule will also be retain on the filter. For example, proteins expressed by different clones of an expression library are bound to a nitrocellulose membrane, by colony (bacterial library) or plaque (phage library) blotting. A labelled protein can then be used as a probe to identify clones expressing proteins that interact with the probe. Interactions occur on the nitrocellulose filters. The method is highly general and therefore widely applicable. A variety of approaches can be used to label the ligand, alternatively the ligand can be detected by a specific antibody." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0048</id>
        <fullname>filamentous phage display</fullname>
        <description>"Filamentous phages (M13, f1, fd) have been extensively used to develop and implement the technology of phage display. Repertoires of relatively short peptides of random amino acid sequences or cDNA libraries have been constructed and searched successfully. Most experiments have taken advantage of the ability to assemble phages decorated with hybrid versions of the receptor protein pIII or of the major coat protein pVIII. Both systems allow the display of foreign peptides by fusion to the amino-terminus of the capsid protein but differ in the number of peptide copies that can be displayed on each phage particle. Display libraries of very diverse protein fragments have been constructed by fusing either genomic or cDNA fragments to gene III or gene VIII." [PMID:7682645]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0053</id>
        <fullname>fluorescence polarization spectroscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Because of the long lifetimes of excited fluorescent molecules (nanoseconds), fluorescence can be used to monitor the rotational motion of molecules, which occurs on this timescale. This is accomplished experimentally by excitation with plane-polarized light, followed by measurement of the emission at parallel and perpendicular planes. Since rotational correlation times depend on the size of the molecule, this method can be used to measure the binding of two proteins because the observed polarization increase when a larger complex is formed. A fluorescence anisotropy experiment is normally carried out with a protein bearing a covalently added fluorescent group, which increases both the observed fluorescence lifetime of the excited state and the intensity of the fluorescent signal. Residue modification can be assessed by addition of an antibody which binds to the modified residue and alters the molecular weight of the complex. A variation of this technique has been used to show interaction of a DNA binding protein with another protein. In this case the DNA rather than protein is fluorescently labelled." [PMID:12805227, PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0054</id>
        <fullname>fluorescence-activated cell sorting</fullname>
        <description>"Cells in suspension flow through a laser beam, the scattered light or emitted fluorescence is measured, filtered and converted to digital values. Cells can be sorted according to their properties. Using flow cytometry, any fluorescent or light scattering experiment can be carried out on entire cells. With this instrument, interactions occurring either on cell surfaces or in any other subcellular location can be studied by using suitable fluorescent labels." [PMID:11988464]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0055</id>
        <fullname>fluorescent resonance energy transfer</fullname>
        <description>"FRET is a quantum mechanical process involving the radiationless transfer of energy from a donor fluorophore to an appropriately positioned acceptor fluorophore. The fluorophores are genetically fused to the protein in analysis and cotransfected. Three basic conditions must be fulfilled for FRET to occur between a donor molecule and acceptor molecule. First, the donor emission spectrum must significantly overlap the absorption spectrum of the acceptor. Second, the distance between the donor and acceptor fluorophores must fall within the range 20 to 100 Angstrom. Third, the donor and acceptor fluorophores must be in favourable orientations." [PMID:11558993]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0051</id>
        <fullname>fluorescence technology</fullname>
        <description>"Techniques based upon the measurement of the emission of one or more photons by a molecule activated by the absorption of a quantum of electro-magnetic radiation. Typically the emission, which is characterised by a wavelength that is longer than the one of excitatory radiation, occurs within 10-8 seconds." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0052</id>
        <fullname>fluorescence correlation spectroscopy</fullname>
        <description>"FCS monitors the random motion of fluorescently labelled molecules inside a defined volume irradiated by a focused laser beam. These fluctuations provide information on the rate of diffusion or diffusion time of a particle and this is directly dependent on the particle mass. As a consequence, any increase in the mass of a biomolecule, e.g. as a result of an interaction with a second molecule, is readily detected as an increase in the diffusion time of the particle. From these results the concentration of the different molecules can be calculated as well as their binding constant." [PMID:10733953]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0362</id>
        <fullname>inference</fullname>
        <description>"Evidence based on human assumption, either when the complete experimental support is not available or when the results are extended by homology to closely related orthologues sequences." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0363</id>
        <fullname>inferred by author</fullname>
        <description>"Evidence based on the author of a paper assumption, either when the complete experimental support is not available or when the results are extended by homology to closely related orthologues sequences." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0364</id>
        <fullname>inferred by curator</fullname>
        <description>"Evidence based on a curator assumption, either when the complete experimental support is not available or when the results are extended by homology to closely related orthologues sequences." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0016</id>
        <fullname>circular dichroism</fullname>
        <description>"Circular dichroism (CD) is observed when optically active molecules absorb left and right hand circularly polarized light slightly differently. Linearly polarized light can be viewed as a superposition of two components of circularly polarized light of equal amplitude and phase but opposite handness. When this light passes through an optically active sample the two polarized components are absorbed differently. The difference in left and right handed absorbance A(l)- A(r) is the signal registered in CD spectra. This signal displays distinct features corresponding to different secondary structures present in peptides, proteins and nucleic acids. The analysis of CD spectra can therefore yield valuable information about the secondary structure of biological macromolecules and the interactions among molecules that influence their structure." [PMID:11578931]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0013</id>
        <fullname>biophysical</fullname>
        <description>"The application of physical principles and methods to biological experiments." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0014</id>
        <fullname>adenylate cyclase complementation</fullname>
        <description>"Adenylate cyclase is encoded by the cyaA gene and contains a catalytic domain which can be proteolytically cleaved into two complementary fragments, T25 and T18, which remain associated in the presence of calmodulin in a fully active ternary complex. In the absence of calmodulin, the mixture of the two fragments does not exhibit detectable activity, suggesting that the two fragments do not associate. When expressed in an adenylate cyclase-deficient E. coli strain (E. coli lacks calmodulin or calmodulin-related proteins), the T25 and T18 fragments fused to putative interacting proteins are brought into close association which result in cAMP synthesis. The level of reconstructed adenylate cyclase can be estimated by monitoring the expression of a cAMP dependent reporter gene." [PMID:9576956]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0019</id>
        <fullname>coimmunoprecipitation</fullname>
        <description>"In this approach an antibody, specific for the molecule of interest (bait) or any tag expressed within a fusion protein, is used to separate the bait from a protein mixture or a cell lysate and to capture its ligand simultaneously. The partners that bind to the bait molecule retained by the resin can then be eluted and identified. The antibody may be free or bound to a matrix during this process." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0017</id>
        <fullname>classical fluorescence spectroscopy</fullname>
        <description>"Proteins contain endogenous fluorophores such as tryptophan residue and heme or flavins groups. Protein folding and protein-protein interaction can be studied by monitoring changes in the tryptophan environment detected by changes in its intrinsic fluorescence. Changes in the fluorescence emission spectrum on complex formation can occur either due to a shift in the wavelength of maximum fluorescence emission or by a shift in fluorescence intensity caused by the mixing of two proteins. The interaction of two proteins causes a shift in the fluorescence emission spectrum relative to the sum of the individual fluorescence spectra, resulting in a difference spectrum [F (complex)-2 F (sum)], which is a measurable effect of the interaction. Loss of fluorescence signal from a substrate can be used to measure protein cleavage." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0018</id>
        <fullname>two hybrid</fullname>
        <description>"The classical two-hybrid system is a method that uses transcriptional activity as a measure of protein-protein interaction. It relies on the modular nature of many site-specific transcriptional activators (GAL 4) , which consist of a DNA-binding domain and a transcriptional activation domain. The DNA-binding domain serves to target the activator to the specific genes that will be expressed, and the activation domain contacts other proteins of the transcriptional machinery to enable transcription to occur. The two-hybrid system is based on the observation that the two domains of the activator need to be non-covalently brought together by the interaction of any two proteins. The application of this system requires the expression of two hybrid. Generally this assay is performed in yeast cell, but it can also be carried out in other organism." [PMID:10967325, PMID:12634794, PMID:1946372]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0020</id>
        <fullname>transmission electron microscopy</fullname>
        <description>"During the treatment for microscope analysis a tissue section is incubated with high-specificity antibodies coupled to heavy metals (gold). Any tissue section can then be analysed by electron microscopy to localise the target proteins within the cell. This method supports very high resolution colocalisation of different molecules in a cell." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0024</id>
        <fullname>confirmational text mining</fullname>
        <description>"Text mining is used to support interactions which have been determined by other methods." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1011</id>
        <fullname>deneddylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"measurement of thereaction that breaks a covalent bond between a Glycine residue of an ubiquitine like NEDD8 protein and a lysine residue of the target." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0026</id>
        <fullname>correlated mutations</fullname>
        <description>"Pairs of multiple alignments of orthologous sequences are used to identify potential interacting partners as proteins that show covariation of their residue identities between different species. Proteins displaying inter-protein correlated mutations during evolution are likely to be interacting proteins due to co-adapted evolution of their protein interacting interfaces." [PMID:11933068]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1010</id>
        <fullname>neddylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of a reversible reaction that create a covalent bond between a Glycine residue of an ubiquitine like NEDD8 protein and a lysine residue of the target." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0027</id>
        <fullname>cosedimentation</fullname>
        <description>"Separation of a protein mixture under the influence of artificial gravity." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0028</id>
        <fullname>cosedimentation in solution</fullname>
        <description>"The ultracentrifuge can be used to characterise and/or purify macromolecules in solution according to their mass and hydrodynamic properties. Sedimentation studies provide information about the molecular weight and shape of a molecule. It is also possible to measure the association state of the sample. Both the mass of a molecule and its shape, that influences the friction forces and diffusion that counterbalances gravity, determine the sedimentation speed." [PMID:10410796]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0029</id>
        <fullname>cosedimentation through density gradient</fullname>
        <description>"Sedimentation through a density gradient measures the sedimentation rate of a mixture of proteins through either a glycerol or sucrose gradient. Two interacting proteins will sediment mostly as a complex at concentrations above the binding constant. By varying the concentration of one or both of the complex constituents and taking into account the dilution of the species during sedimentation, one can reasonably accurately estimate the binding constant." [PMID:10410796]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1009</id>
        <fullname>desumoylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the reaction that breaks a covalent bond between a C-terminus G of an ubiquitine like sumo protein and a K residue of the target." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1007</id>
        <fullname>glycosylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the covalent attachment of a glycosyl residue to one or more monomeric units in a polypeptide, polynucleotide, polysaccharide, or other biological polymer." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0030</id>
        <fullname>cross-linking study</fullname>
        <description>"Analysis of complexes obtained by chemical treatments that promote the formation of covalent bonds among molecules in close proximity." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1008</id>
        <fullname>sumoylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the reversible reaction that creates a covalent bond between a C-terminus G of an ubiquitine like sumo protein and a K residue of the target." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1005</id>
        <fullname>adp ribosylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the addition of one or more ADP-ribose moieties to proteins." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1006</id>
        <fullname>deglycosylase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the hydrolysis of the beta-aspartylglycosylamine bond of aspargine-linked glycopeptides and glycoproteins." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0031</id>
        <fullname>protein cross-linking with a bifunctional reagent</fullname>
        <description>"A cross-linker is a bifunctional molecule having two reactive ends linked by a spacer, often containing a disulfide bond. Cross-linkers induce the formation of covalent bonds among proteins that are neighbours. When a reducing agent is added the disulfide bridge is cleaved, the cross-linked pairs are released and can be identified. There are various classes of cross-linkers, the most common are those having photoreactive groups that become reactive fluorophores when activated by UV light thereby resulting in photolabeling the cross-linked moieties." [PMID:10679368, PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1003</id>
        <fullname>geranylgeranylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the attachment of one or two 20-carbon lipophilic geranylgeranyl isoprene units from geranylgeranyl diphosphate to one or more cysteine residue(s)." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0034</id>
        <fullname>display technology</fullname>
        <description>"All the methods that permit the physical linking of a protein/peptide to its coding sequence. As a consequence affinity purification of the displayed peptide results in the genetic enrichment of its coding sequence. By these technologies genes encoding a peptide with desired binding properties can be selected over an excess of up to 1012 unrelated molecules." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:1004</id>
        <fullname>palmitoylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the covalent attachment of palmitic acid to a protein." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0994</id>
        <fullname>demyristoylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"measures the removal of N6-myristoyl-L-lysine, which is cleaved and returns a K residue." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0995</id>
        <fullname>depalmitoylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the removal of S-palmitoyl-L-cysteine, N6-palmitoyl-L-lysine, O-palmitoyl-L-threonine or O-palmitoyl-L-serine, which are cleaved and return C,K,T or S residues."</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0992</id>
        <fullname>defarnesylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the removal of S-farnesyl-L-cysteined, which is cleaved and returns a C residue." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0993</id>
        <fullname>degeranylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the removal of S-geranylgeranyl-L-cysteine, which is cleaved and returns a C residue." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0998</id>
        <fullname>deubiquination assay></fullname>
        <description>"Measures the cleavage of the G-K bond and release of ubiquitin or ubiquitin like proteins." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0999</id>
        <fullname>formylase assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measurement of the reaction that can affect K or G residues. Reside is functionalised with a formyl group." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0996</id>
        <fullname>deformylation assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the removal of N6-formyl-L-lysine, which is cleaved and returns a K residue." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0997</id>
        <fullname>ubiquitination assay</fullname>
        <description>"Measures the reversible reaction that creates a covalent bond between a C-terminus G of ubiquitin and a K residue of the target." [PMID:14760721]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0006</id>
        <fullname>anti bait coimmunoprecipitation</fullname>
        <description>"A specific antibody for the molecule of interest (bait) is available, this is used to generate a high affinity resin to capture the endogenous bait present in a sample." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0007</id>
        <fullname>anti tag coimmunoprecipitation</fullname>
        <description>"A specific antibody for the molecule of interest is not available, therefore the bait protein is expressed as a hybrid protein fused to a tag peptide/protein for which efficient and specific antibodies or a specific ligand are available." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0008</id>
        <fullname>array technology</fullname>
        <description>"In this class of methodologies, the molecules to be tested are presented ordered in an array format (typically at high density) on planar supports. The characteristics and chemical nature of the planar support can vary. This format permits the simultaneous assay, in controlled conditions, of several thousand proteins/peptides/nucleic acids for different functions, for instance their ability to bind any given molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0009</id>
        <fullname>bacterial display</fullname>
        <description>"The protein of interest is presented on the outer membrane of Gram negative bacteria by expressing it as a fusion partner to peptide signals that direct heterologous proteins to the cell surface. For instance, a single chain Fv (scFv) antibody fragment, consisting of the variable heavy and variable light domains from two separate anti-digoxin monoclonal antibodies, was displayed on the outer membrane of Escherichia coli by fusing it to an Lpp-OmpA. Similar systems have also been developed for gram positive bacteria. Fluorescence-activated cell sorting (FACS), is used to specifically select clones displaying a protein binding to scFv-producing cells." [PMID:10436088, PMID:8248129]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0004</id>
        <fullname>affinity chromatography technology</fullname>
        <description>"This class of approaches is characterised by the use of affinity resins as tools to purify molecule of interest (baits) and their binding partners. The baits can be captured by a variety of high affinity ligands linked to a resin - for example, antibodies specific for the bait itself, antibodies for specific tags engineered to be expressed as part of the bait or other high affinity binders such as glutathione resins for GST fusion proteins, metal resins for histidine-tagged proteins." [PMID:7708014]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0398</id>
        <fullname>two hybrid pooling approach</fullname>
        <description>"In the pooling strategy the sets of bait and prey hybrid vectors are randomly mated. The positives double hybrid clones are the interacting partners." [PMID:12634794, PMID for application instance:11283351]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0399</id>
        <fullname>two hybrid fragment pooling approach</fullname>
        <description>"This two hybrid approach involves the screening of a large number of individual proteins against a comprehensive library of randomly generated fragment as prey. The usage of degenerated fragment allows identification of the minimal protein region required for the interaction. Since multiple clones that encode overlapping regions of protein are often identified, the minimal domain for interaction may be readily apparent from the initial screen." [PMID:12634794, PMID for application instance:11196647]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0010</id>
        <fullname>beta galactosidase complementation</fullname>
        <description>"Beta-galactosidase activity can be used to monitor the interaction of chimeric proteins. Pairs of inactive beta gal deletion mutants are capable of complementing to restore activity when fused to interacting protein partners. Critical to the success of this system is the choice of two poorly complementing mutant moieties, since strongly complementing mutants spontaneously assemble and produce functional beta-gal activity detectable in absence of any fused protein fragment." [PMID:12042868, PMID:9237989]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0012</id>
        <fullname>bioluminescence resonance energy transfer</fullname>
        <description>"In this variation of the FRET assay the donor fluorophore is replaced by a luciferase (typically Renilla luciferase). In the presence of its substrate, the luciferase catalyses a bioluminescent reaction that excites the acceptor fluorophore through a resonance energy transfer mechanism. As with FRET the energy transfer occurs only if the protein fused to the luciferase and the one fused to the acceptor fluorophore are in close proximity (10-100 Angstrom)." [PMID:9874787, PMID for application instance:10725388]</description>
      </evidence>
      <evidence>
        <id>MI:0011</id>
        <fullname>beta lactamase complementation</fullname>
        <description>"This strategy is based on a protein fragment complementation assay (PCA) of the enzyme TEM-1 beta-lactamase. The approach includes a simple colorimetric in vitro assays using the cephalosporin nitrocefin and assays in intact cells using the fluorescent substrate CCF2/AM. The combination of in vitro colorimetric and in vivo fluorescence assays of beta-lactamase in mammalian cells permits a variety of sensitive and high-throughput large-scale applications." [PMID:12042868]</description>
      </evidence>
    </evidences>
    <conceptclasses>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0902</id>
        <fullname>rna cleavage</fullname>
        <description>"Any process by which an RNA molecule is cleaved at specific sites or in a regulated manner." [GO:0006396, PMID:14681407]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0910</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0844</id>
        <fullname>phosphotransfer reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reaction where a phosphate is transferred between two proteins of a phosphorelay system. " [PMID:14755292, PMID:16712436]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0904</id>
        <fullname>Polysaccharide</fullname>
        <description>"A polysaccharide is a complex polymer of carbohydrate monormers. They are polymers made up of many monosaccharides joined together by glycosidic bonds. They are therefore very large, often branched, macromolecules." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0881</id>
        <fullname>nucleoside triphosphatase reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Catalysis of the hydrolysis of a  nucleoside triphosphate into a nucleoside diphosphate plus phosphate." [GO:0017111, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0701</id>
        <fullname>dna strand elongation</fullname>
        <description>"The process by which a DNA strand is synthesized from template DNA by the action of polymerases, which add nucleotides to the 3' end of the nascent DNA strand." [GO:0006271, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0986</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>Localizable</id>
        <fullname>Localizable</fullname>
        <description>An abstract or physical concept that can have a location.</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0800</id>
        <fullname>single nonmonotonic genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation of B shows opposing effects in the WT and a backgrounds</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0212</id>
        <fullname>lipid cleavage reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Cleavage of a lipid group covalently bound to a protein residue." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0194</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MolCmplx</id>
        <fullname>Molecule Complex</fullname>
        <description>An entity comprised of one or more molecules</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0801</id>
        <fullname>double nonmonotonic genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation of both A and B show opposing effects in the WT background and the background with the other mutant gene. E.g., WT >= ab > a >= b" [PMID:15833125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0211</id>
        <fullname>lipid addition</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent or non covalent binding of lipid group on a protein residue." [GO:0006497, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0214</id>
        <fullname>myristoylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Irreversible covalent addition of a myristoyl group via an amide bond to the alpha-amino group of an amino acid. Reaction that can affect K or G residues." [GO:0018319, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0059, RESID:AA0078]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0211</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0213</id>
        <fullname>methylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"The covalent attachment of a methyl residue to one or more monomeric units in a polypeptide, polynucleotide, polysaccharide, or other biological polymer. Irreversible reaction that can affect A,G,M,F,P,C,R,N,Q,E,H,or K residues." [GO:0043414, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0061, RESID:AA0062, RESID:AA0063, RESID:AA0064, RESID:AA0065, RESID:AA0066, RESID:AA0067, RESID:AA0068, RESID:AA0069, RESID:AA0070, RESID:AA0071, RESID:AA0072, RESID:AA0073, RESID:AA0074, RESID:AA0075, RESID:AA0076, RESID:AA0234, RESID:AA0272]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0216</id>
        <fullname>palmitoylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent attachment of palmitic acid to the cysteine residues of membrane proteins. Reversible reaction that can affect C,K,T or S residues." [GO:0018318, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0060, RESID:AA0077, RESID:AA0079, RESID:AA0080, RESID:AA0106]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0211</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0217</id>
        <fullname>phosphorylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reversible reaction that can affect D,C,H,S,T,Y,R residues." [GO:0016310, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0033, RESID:AA0034, RESID:AA0035, RESID:AA0036, RESID:AA0037, RESID:AA0038, RESID:AA0039, RESID:AA0222]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0407</id>
        <fullname>direct interaction</fullname>
        <description>"Interaction that is proven to involve only its interactors." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0915</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0408</id>
        <fullname>disulfide bond</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent bond mediated by 2 sulfur atoms." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0195</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0220</id>
        <fullname>ubiquitination reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reversible reaction that create a covalent bond between a C-terminus G of ubiquitin and a K residue of the target." [GO:0016567, PMID:11583613, RESID:AA0125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0871</id>
        <fullname>demethylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"The cleavage of a methyl group from a polypeptide. Methylation is generally an irreversible reaction except in mamalian." [GO:0006482, PMID:17277772]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0945</id>
        <fullname>oxidoreductase activity electron transfer reaction</fullname>
        <description>"An oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GO:GO\:0016491, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0403</id>
        <fullname>colocalization</fullname>
        <description>"Coincident occurrence of molecules in a given subcellular fraction observed with a low resolution methodology from which a physical interaction among those molecules cannot be inferred." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Interaction</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0987</id>
        <fullname>rna strand elongation</fullname>
        <description>"The process by which an RNA strand is synthesized from template DNA by the action of polymerases, which add nucleotides to the 3' end of the nascent RNA strand." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0986</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0986</id>
        <fullname>nucleic acid strand elongation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"The lengthening of a strand of a nucleic acid by the systematic addition of bases by a polymerase." [PMID:159156]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0985</id>
        <fullname>deamination reaction</fullname>
        <description>"The removal of an amine group from a molecule." [PMID:14760721]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>Thing</id>
        <fullname>Thing</fullname>
        <description>All concepts</description>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>Interaction</id>
        <fullname>Interaction</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0679</id>
        <fullname>PolyAdenine</fullname>
        <description>"A sequence of adenine nucleotides that is added to the 3' end of some primary transcript messenger RNA molecules in eukaryotes during post-transcriptional processing. The added tail is believed to confer stability to the molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>Participant</id>
        <fullname>Participant</fullname>
        <description>A molecular biological entity that can participate in a Process or in an Interaction.</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Localizable</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>Polynucleotide</id>
        <fullname>Polynucleotide</fullname>
        <description>A polymer of nucleotides</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>RNA</id>
        <fullname>RNA</fullname>
        <description>Ribonucleic Acid. A polymer of riboses with pyrimidine and purine bases.</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0930</id>
        <fullname>epistatic genetic interaction</fullname>
        <description>"The genetic interaction between a group of genes, in which the effects of an allele of one member gene of the group hide the effects of alleles of other genes in the group." [PMID:11988766]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0935</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>Molecule</id>
        <fullname>Molecule</fullname>
        <description>A molecule is comprised of one or more atoms that form a single component through
                        covalent bonds.</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0931</id>
        <fullname>genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"Two genes A and B present an genetic interaction defined by inequality  if the phenotypes of the two single mutants a and b, the double mutant  ab and the wild-type WT can be measured quantitatively and described  relative to each other by an inequality relationship." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0208</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0932</id>
        <fullname>noninteractive genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"Mutation that has no effect in the WT and b backgrounds, or b has no effect in the a and WT backgrounds, or both hold true. E. g., WT = a > b = ab." [PMID:15833125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0933</id>
        <fullname>negative genetic interaction</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype of the double mutant ab is stronger than expected from the combination of the individual effects of a and b." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0208</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0882</id>
        <fullname>atpase reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Catalysis of the hydrolisis of ATP+ H2O = ADP + phosphate." [GO:0016887, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0881</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0934</id>
        <fullname>neutral genetic interaction</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype of the double mutant ab is equal to the phenotype expected from the combination of the individual effects of a and b." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0208</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0971</id>
        <fullname>phosphopantetheinylation</fullname>
        <description>"The posttranslational phosphopantetheinylation of peptidyl-serine to form peptidyl-O-phosphopantetheine-L-serine." [PMID:19679086]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0883</id>
        <fullname>gtpase reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Catalysis of the hydrolisis of GTP+ H2O = GDP + phosphate." [GO:0003924, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0881</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0935</id>
        <fullname>positive genetic interaction</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype of the double mutant ab is weaker than expected from the combination of the individual effects of a and b." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0208</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0566</id>
        <fullname>sumoylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reversible reaction that create a covalent bond between a C-terminus G of an ubiquitine like sumo protein and a K residue of the target." [GO:0016925, PMID:15985640]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0567</id>
        <fullname>neddylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reversible reaction that create a covalent bond between a Glycine residue of an ubiquitine like NEDD8 protein and a lysine residue of the target." [GO:0045116, PMID:16127432]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0568</id>
        <fullname>desumoylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Cleavage of the G-K bond and release of the SUMO ubiquitin like proteins." [GO:0016926, PMID:15985640]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0569</id>
        <fullname>deneddylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Cleavage of the G-K bond and release of the NEDD8 ubiquitin like proteins. Deneddylation, which removes the NEDD8 moiety, requires the isopeptidase activity of the COP9 signalosome." [GO:0000338, PMID:16127432]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0611</id>
        <fullname>Signal recognition particle rna</fullname>
        <description>"Small (300 nucleotides) stable RNAs transcribed by RNA pol III that are part of the signal-recognition particle (SRP). This particle comprises one RNA and six proteins bound to the RNA. SRP function is to assist secretory proteins sorting in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). SRP is a cytosolic particle that transiently binds to the ER signal sequence of a nascent protein, to the large ribosomal unit, and to the SRP receptor in the ER membrane." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0571</id>
        <fullname>mrna cleavage</fullname>
        <description>"Any process by which a pre-mRNA or mRNA molecule is cleaved at specific sites or in a regulated manner." [GO:0006379, PMID:14681407]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0902</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0570</id>
        <fullname>protein cleavage</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent modification of a polypeptide occuring during its maturation or its proteolytic degradation." [PMID:14744292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0194</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0233</id>
        <fullname>Protein-DNA complex</fullname>
        <description>"A stable set of interacting protein and DNA that can be copurified and operate as a functional unit." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0572</id>
        <fullname>dna cleavage</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent bond breakage of a DNA molecule leading to the formation of smaller fragments." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0910</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0797</id>
        <fullname>epistatic genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation of A and B have different effects (in terms of direction or magnitude) on the wild-type background and the double mutant has the same phenotype as either A or B</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0321</id>
        <fullname>Catalytic RNA</fullname>
        <description>"Species of RNA that catalyses cleavage or trans-esterification of the phosphodiester link." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0796</id>
        <fullname>suppressive genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation of A has an effect on WT, but that effect is abolished by adding the suppressor b, which itself shows no single-mutant effect. E. g., WT = b = ab > a." [PMID:15833125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0322</id>
        <fullname>GuideRNA</fullname>
        <description>"Small RNA molecules that hybridize to specific mRNAs and direct their RNA editing." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0795</id>
        <fullname>asynthetic genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation of A alone,   B alone and AB combined have the same effect on the WT background. E. g., WT > a = b = ab." [PMID:15833125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0323</id>
        <fullname>Heterogeneous nuclear RNA</fullname>
        <description>"A heterogeneous mixture of RNA molecules with a rapid turnover rate that occurs in cell nuclei during protein synthesis; it is the form of RNA synthesized in eukaryotes by RNA polymerase II, which is translated into protein." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>InfoPolymer</id>
        <fullname>InfoPolymer</fullname>
        <description>A polymeric molecule that contains sequence information.</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Molecule</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0794</id>
        <fullname>synthetic genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation a and the phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation b have no effect on the WT background, but the combined genetic perturbation of A and B has a phenotypic effect. E. g., WT = a = b > ab." [PMID:15833125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0799</id>
        <fullname>additive genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"Single-mutant phenotype effects combine to give a double-mutant effect different from the wild type and different from single mutant effect.</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0327</id>
        <fullname>Peptide</fullname>
        <description>"Chains of amino acids joined by peptide bonds. Distinction between peptides, oligopeptides and polypeptides is arbitrarily by length; a polypeptide is perhaps more than 15 residues." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Molecule</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0798</id>
        <fullname>conditional genetic interaction defined by inequality</fullname>
        <description>"The phenotype resulting from genetic perturbation of A has an effect only in the b background, or the b mutant has an effect only in the a background. a has an effect only in the b background, or the b mutant has an effect only in the a background. E. g., WT = a > ab > b or WT > a > b > ab." [PMID:15833125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0931</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0209</id>
        <fullname>geranylgeranylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Attachment of one or two 20-carbon lipophilic geranylgeranyl isoprene units from geranylgeranyl diphosphate to one or more cysteine residue(s).Reversible reaction that can affect C residue." [GO:0018348, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0104]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0211</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0208</id>
        <fullname>genetic interaction</fullname>
        <description>"Two genes A and B \"genetically interact\" when the phenotype generated as the result of mutations in both genes (double mutant ab) is unexpectedly not just a combination of the phenotypes of the two single mutants a and b." [PMID:16527956]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Interaction</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0192</id>
        <fullname>acetylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reaction, that can affect K,C,A,D,E,Q,G,I,K,M,P,S,T,Y,V residues." [GO:0006473, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0041, RESID:AA0042, RESID:AA0043, RESID:AA0044, RESID:AA0045, RESID:AA0046, RESID:AA0047, RESID:AA0048, RESID:AA0049, RESID:AA0050, RESID:AA0051, RESID:AA0052, RESID:AA0053, RESID:AA0054, RESID:AA0055, RESID:AA0056]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0207</id>
        <fullname>formylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reaction that can affect K or G residues. Reside is functionalised with a formyl group." [GO:0018256, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0057, RESID:AA0211]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0193</id>
        <fullname>amidation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Irreversible reaction that can affect A,R,N,D,C,Q,E,G,H,I,L,K,M,F,P,S,T,W,Y or V residues." [GO:0001519, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0081, RESID:AA0082, RESID:AA0083, RESID:AA0084, RESID:AA0085, RESID:AA0086, RESID:AA0087, RESID:AA0088, RESID:AA0089, RESID:AA0090, RESID:AA0091, RESID:AA0092, RESID:AA0093, RESID:AA0094, RESID:AA0095, RESID:AA0096, RESID:AA0097, RESID:AA0098, RESID:AA0099, RESID:AA0100]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0206</id>
        <fullname>farnesylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reversible reaction that can affect C residue." [GO:0018347, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0102]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0211</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0194</id>
        <fullname>cleavage reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent bond breakage in a molecule leading to the formation of smaller molecules." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0195</id>
        <fullname>covalent binding</fullname>
        <description>"Interaction leading to the formation of covalent bond within an autocatalytic molecule or between partners." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0407</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0204</id>
        <fullname>deubiquitination reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Cleavage of the G-K bond and release of ubiquitin or ubiquitin like proteins." [GO:0016579, PMID:11583613, RESID:AA0125]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0558</id>
        <fullname>deglycosylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Reaction catalyzed by PNGase, a deglycosylating enzyme that promotes the hydrolysis of the beta-aspartylglycosylamine bond of aspargine-linked glycopeptides and glycoproteins." [GO:0006517, PMID:15670854]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0203</id>
        <fullname>dephosphorylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Phosphoresidues are cleaved and return D,C,H,S,T,Y or R residues." [GO:0016311, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0033, RESID:AA0034, RESID:AA0035, RESID:AA0036, RESID:AA0037, RESID:AA0038, RESID:AA0039, RESID:AA0222]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0197</id>
        <fullname>deacetylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"N6-acetyl-L-lysine or S-acetyl-L-cysteine are cleaved and return K or C residues." [GO:0006476, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0055, RESID:AA0056]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0559</id>
        <fullname>glycosylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"The covalent attachment of a glycosyl residue to one or more monomeric units in a polypeptide, polynucleotide, polysaccharide, or other biological polymer. Reaction that can affect Ser, Thr, Cys, Arg, and Asn residues. This reaction is known to be reversible in the case of Asn substrate." [GO:0043413, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0122, RESID:AA0151, RESID:AA0154, RESID:AA0155, RESID:AA0327]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0202</id>
        <fullname>depalmitoylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"S-palmitoyl-L-cysteine, N6-palmitoyl-L-lysine, O-palmitoyl-L-threonine or O-palmitoyl-L-serine are cleaved and return C,K,T or S residues." [PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0060, RESID:AA0077, RESID:AA0106]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0212</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0198</id>
        <fullname>defarnesylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"S-farnesyl-L-cysteined is cleaved and returns a C residue." [PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0102]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0212</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0556</id>
        <fullname>transglutamination reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Gln-Lys cross-link catalyzed by a transglutaminase." [PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0124]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0195</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0201</id>
        <fullname>demyristoylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"N6-myristoyl-L-lysine is cleaved and returns a K residue." [PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0078]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0212</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0199</id>
        <fullname>deformylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"N6-formyl-L-lysine is cleaved and returns a K residue." [PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0211]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0557</id>
        <fullname>adp ribosylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Involves the addition of one or more ADP-ribose moieties to proteins. Reaction that can affect Arg, Cys, Glu, Arg and Asn residues." [GO:0006471, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0168, RESID:AA0169, RESID:AA0231, RESID:AA0237, RESID:AA0295]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0200</id>
        <fullname>degeranylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"S-geranylgeranyl-L-cysteine is cleaved and returns a C residue." [PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0104]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0212</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0210</id>
        <fullname>hydroxylation reaction</fullname>
        <description>"Irreversible introduction of a hydroxyl group that can affect K,P,Y or R residues. Hydroxylation is the first step in the oxidative degeneration of organic compounds." [GO:0018126, PMID:14755292, RESID:AA0028, RESID:AA0029, RESID:AA0030, RESID:AA0146, RESID:AA0215]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0414</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0910</id>
        <fullname>nucleic acid cleavage</fullname>
        <description>"Covalent bond breakage of a nucleic acid molecule leading to the formation of smaller fragments." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0194</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0414</id>
        <fullname>enzymatic reaction</fullname>
        <description>"terms aiming to represent biochemical reactions referring to their resulting product modifications." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0407</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0316</id>
        <fullname>Ribonucleoprotein complex</fullname>
        <description>"A macromolecular complex containing both protein and RNA molecules." [GO:0030529, PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Thing</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0914</id>
        <fullname>association</fullname>
        <description>"Molecules that are experimentally shown to be associated potentially by sharing just one interactor. Often associated molecules are co-purified by a pull-down or coimmunoprecipitation and share the same bait molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>Interaction</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
      <cc>
        <id>MI:0915</id>
        <fullname>physical association</fullname>
        <description>"Molecules that are experimentally shown to belong to the same functional or structural complex." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0914</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </cc>
    </conceptclasses>
    <relationtypes>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0684</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_ancillary</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule required for an observed binary interaction to occur. This molecule may act as stabilizer of any of the interaction partners or may act as a bridge molecule between them but the method does not provide resolution or evidence to demonstrate its actual molecular function (i.e.Mudpit, tri hybrid etc)." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0843</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_phosphate_acceptor</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule to which a phosphate may be transferred from a phosphate donor." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0919</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>physical</id>
        <fullname>has_physical_relation_with</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>r</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0842</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_phosphate_donor</fullname>
        <description>"Any molecule that is able to transfer an phosphate to another chemical species." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0918</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>part_act</id>
        <fullname>participates_actively_in</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>has_active_participant</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>true</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>participates_in</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0840</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_stimulator</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule stimulating an interaction by interacting with one or more of the participants." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>phys_intbio</id>
        <fullname>physical_IB_relation</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>physical_IB_relation</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>physical</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0586</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_inhibitor</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule inhibiting an interaction by interacting with one or more of its participants." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0496</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_bait</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_pass</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0941</id>
        <fullname>participates_through_competitive_binding</fullname>
        <description>"Binds to the bait molecule in competition with other prey molecules, for example at a shared binding site." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0898</id>
        <fullname>participates_putatively_self_binding</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule that is reported to self-interact but the experimental condition does not allow to resolve whether the interaction is intramolecular (true self interaction) or intermolecular (homodimer)." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>inferred_from</id>
        <fullname>inferred_from</fullname>
        <description>Interaction->Interaction</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>phys_intbio</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>observed_in</id>
        <fullname>observed_in</fullname>
        <description>Interaction -> Experiment</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>phys_intbio</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>part_pass</id>
        <fullname>participates_passively_in</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>has_passive_participant</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>true</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>participates_in</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>participates_in</id>
        <fullname>participates_in</fullname>
        <description>Participant->Process</description>
        <inverseName>has_participant</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>true</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>phys_intbio</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0579</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_electron_donor</fullname>
        <description>"Any molecule that is able to transfer an electron to another chemical species." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0918</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0498</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_prey</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0497</id>
        <fullname>participates_neutrally</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>participates_in</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0582</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_suppressed_gene</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_pass</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0581</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_suppressor_gene</fullname>
        <description></description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0580</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_electron_acceptor</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule to which and electron may be transferred from an electron donor." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0919</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>r</id>
        <fullname>is related to</fullname>
        <description>Root relation type</description>
        <inverseName>is related to</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>true</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0918</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_donor</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule which emits electrons or ions that are transfered to an acceptor molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0919</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_acceptor</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule able to receive electrons or ions from a donor molecule." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0503</id>
        <fullname>participates_self_binding</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule that makes intramolecular interactions." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>MI:0898</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0682</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_cofactor</fullname>
        <description>"A cofactor is a small molecule required for the catalysis of an enzyme." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0501</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_enzyme</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule catalyzing a modification on its interacting partner." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_act</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
      <relation_type>
        <id>MI:0502</id>
        <fullname>participates_as_enzyme_target</fullname>
        <description>"Molecule that is the target of its binding partner catalytic activity." [PMID:14755292]</description>
        <inverseName>none</inverseName>
        <isAntisymmetric>false</isAntisymmetric>
        <isReflexive>false</isReflexive>
        <isSymmetric>false</isSymmetric>
        <isTransitive>false</isTransitive>
        <specialisationOf>
          <idRef>part_pass</idRef>
        </specialisationOf>
      </relation_type>
    </relationtypes>
  </ondexmetadata>
</ondexdata>